(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-01T13:07:44.250937",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
Lonely ロリロリ神、降臨
The lonely loli-loli god has descended,
鐘を鳴らせばこの通り
If you ring the bell, right on cue,
これは救済のレクイエム
This is the requiem of salvation.
せーのっ
Ready, set—
触ったら逮捕! (Ah!)
Touch me and you're under arrest! (Ah!)
獄中♥で点呼! (Uh!)
Roll call inside the prison! (Uh!)
いち、に、さん、しー?
One, two, three, four?
(ごめんなさい)
(We're so sorry!)
はぁ? (ﾟДﾟ) ごめんなさいが、きこえない
Huh? (ﾟДﾟ) I can't hear your apology!
(えーん!)
(Eh~!)
粛聖!ロリ神レクイエム☆
Purification! Loli-god Requiem☆
将来はお前なんかには
In the future, I wouldn't want
好かれたくない
To be liked by someone like you
泥水で口を洗え
Wash your mouth out with muddy water,
法廷で会おうね♥
Let's meet in court?♥ (Right?)
さぁ おまわりさん
Come on, Mr. Officer,
連れて行って
Take them away,
妄想しか取り柄のない かわいそうな人
Pitiful people whose only asset is delusion.
(ういちゃん!ういちゃん!待ってよおういちゃん!)
(Ui-chan! Ui-chan! Wait for us, Ui-chan!)
その姿親に見せられますか?
Can you show that appearance to your parents?
(ういちゃん!ういちゃん!かわいいよー!)
(Ui-chan! Ui-chan! So cute!)
わぁ、ありがとうございます。お疲れ様です^^
Wah, thank you. Good job~^^
ロリロリ神、降臨
The loli-loli god has descended,
(ずっきゅーん!)
(Zuk-kyuun!)
マジヤバ奴等に用心
Watch out for seriously creepy weirdos,
(ばっきゅーん!)
(Bak-kyuun!)
まともじじゃないなら
If you're not decent,
早く消えてください
Hurry up and disappear.
Lovely ロリロリ神、降臨
Lovely loli-loli god has descended,
(ずっきゅーん!)
(Zuk-kyuun!)
鐘を鳴らせばこの通り
If you ring the bell, right on cue,
(Yes!)
とても優しくて
Such a kind and wonderful big brother,
素敵なお兄ちゃん
楽園でほらねんねしなさい
Go ahead and sleep tight in paradise.
(ういちゃん、ういちゃん、ういちゃん、ういちゃん!)
(Ui-chan, Ui-chan, Ui-chan, Ui-chan!)
ほら。世の中には、こんなに気持ち悪い人たちが蔓延しているんです!
Look. In this world, there are so many disgusting people running rampant!
みーんな、晒し上げますよ。
I'm going to expose all of you!
触ったら逮捕! (Ah!) 獄中♥で点呼! (Uh!)
Touch me and you're under arrest! (Ah!) Roll call inside the prison! (Uh!)
いち、に、さん、しー? (ごめんなさい)
One, two, three, four? (We're so sorry!)
はぁ? (ﾟДﾟ) ごめんなさいが、きこえない (えーん!)
Huh? (ﾟДﾟ) I can't hear your apology! (Eh~!)
粛聖!ロリ神レクイエム☆
Purification! Loli-god Requiem☆
はぁーい、獄中にいるみなしゃーん! 刑務所ファンミーティングのお時間でぇす
Haa-i! Everyone in prison, it's time for the prison fan meeting!
その腐りきった耳を ごりごりかっぱじいて よーう聴いてくださいね
Clean out those rotten ears of yours with a good scraping, and listen very carefully, kay?
ざぁーこ (~たすかる~)
Trash (~Saved~)
きもきも (~たすかる~)
Gross gross (~Saved~)
うるさい (~たすかる~)
Noisy (~Saved~)
黙ってもらっていいですか? (~たすかる~)
Can you please just shut up? (~Saved~)
嫌いです (~たすかる~)
I hate you (~Saved~)
かわいそ (~たすかる~)
Pitiful (~Saved~)
だぁさいw どうしようもない お兄ちゃんお姉ちゃん もう希望もない ゴミだおまえら
How pathetic, how utterly unseemly w Hopeless big brothers and big sisters, you're garbage!
汚物消毒百十番 固有結界は・つ・ど・う♥ 粛聖☆ういびーむ――――――あーーーーーーっ~~~
Disinfect filth, call 110, Reality Marble—♥ Purification☆Ui Beam—— Aaaaaaa~~~
もういちちゅ! ういびーむ――――――あーーーーーーっ~~~
One more time! Ui Beam—— Aaaaaaa~~~
まだまだぁ! ういびーむ――――――あーーーーーーっ~~~
Still not enough! Ui Beam—— Aaaaaaa~~~
怒りの火。セナるインターネットに ういびーむ――――――あーーーーーーっ~~~
The fire of wrath, upon the sacred internet, Ui Beam—— Aaaaaaa~~~
血の雨が降りそそいだ日。愚かなロリコンを…
The day when a rain of blood poured down. Foolish lolicons...
骨の髄まで浄化する、ういびーむ――
Purified down to the marrow of their bones, Ui Beam——
ひと筋の光。それが、ういびーむなのである。
A single ray of light. That is what the Ui Beam is.
「うい物は、すべてを許します…」
"Ui forgives everything..."
ああ、この世の醜さを 集めて描いてみるよ
Ah, gathering the ugliness of this world, I'll try to draw it.
まっ白なcanvasが ケガれて泣いている
The pure white canvas Is crying while getting stained.
Lonely 振り向いた少女は そっと手を掴む…
Lonely, the turned-around girl Softly grabs my hand...
「楽園などないから」
"Because there is no paradise."
おっきいのお友達ののみんなへ おまえらが打ち込んできている虚無には
To all you big kids out there, What meaning is there in the nihilism you're pouring out?
何の意味があるの? ねえ、教えて。うい、ぜんぜーんわかんないんだ!
Hey, tell me. Ui doesn't get it at all!
ロリロリ神、降臨 (ずっきゅーん!)
The loli-loli god has descended, (Zuk-kyuun!)
さよなら笑顔でバイバイ (ばっきゅーん!)
Say goodbye with a smile, bye-bye, (Bak-kyuun!)
ピリオドをどうぞ この手でおしてあげゆ
Go ahead and press the period, I'll push it with my own hand for you.
Lovely ロリロリ神、降臨 (ずっきゅーん!)
Lovely loli-loli god has descended, (Zuk-kyuun!)
鐘を鳴らせばこの通り (Yes!)
If you ring the bell, right on cue, (Yes!)
とても優しくて 素敵なお兄ちゃん
Such a kind and wonderful big brother,
楽園でほらねんねしなさい
Go ahead and sleep tight in paradise.
それが救済のレクイエム せーのっ
This is the requiem of salvation. Ready, set—
触ったら逮捕! (Ah!)
Touch me and you're under arrest! (Ah!)
獄中♥で点呼! (Uh!)
Roll call inside the prison! (Uh!)
いち、に、さん、しー? (ごめんなさい)
One, two, three, four? (We're so sorry!)
はぁ? (ﾟДﾟ) ごめんなさいが、きこえない (えーん!)
Huh? (ﾟДﾟ) I can't hear your apology! (Eh~!)
粛聖!ロリ神レクイエム☆
Purification! Loli-god Requiem☆
将来はお前なんかには好かれたくない
In the future, I wouldn't want to be liked by someone like you
泥水で口を洗え 法廷で会おうね♥
Wash your mouth out with muddy water, Let's meet in court?♥
さぁ おまわりさん 連れて行って 妄想しか取り柄のない
Come on, Mr. Officer, Take them away, Pitiful people...
(ういちゃん!ういちゃん!待ってよおういちゃん!)
(Ui-chan! Ui-chan! Wait for us, Ui-chan!)
その姿親に見せられますか?
Can you show that appearance to your parents?
(ういちゃん!ういちゃん!かわいいよー!)
(Ui-chan! Ui-chan! So cute!)
わぁ、ありがとうございます。お疲れ様です^^
Wah, thank you. Good job~^^
ロリロリ神、降臨 (ずっきゅーん!)
The loli-loli god has descended, (Zuk-kyuun!)
マジヤバ奴等に用心 (ばっきゅーん!)
Watch out for seriously creepy weirdos, (Bak-kyuun!)
まともじじゃないなら 早く消えてください
If you're not decent, Hurry up and disappear.
Lovely ロリロリ神、降臨 (ずっきゅーん!)
Lovely loli-loli god has descended, (Zuk-kyuun!)
鐘を鳴らせばこの通り (Yes!)
If you ring the bell, right on cue, (Yes!)
とても優しくて 素敵なお兄ちゃん
Such a kind and wonderful big brother,
楽園でほらねんねしなさい
Go ahead and sleep tight in paradise.
(ういちゃん、ういちゃん、ういちゃん、ういちゃん!)
(Ui-chan, Ui-chan, Ui-chan, Ui-chan!)
ほら。世の中には、こんなに気持ち悪い人たちが蔓延しているんです!
Look. In this world, there are so many disgusting people running rampant!
みーんな、晒し上げますよ。
I'm going to expose all of you!
触ったら逮捕! (Ah!) 獄中♥で点呼! (Uh!)
Touch me and you're under arrest! (Ah!) Roll call inside the prison! (Uh!)
いち、に、さん、しー? (ごめんなさい)
One, two, three, four? (We're so sorry!)
はぁ? (ﾟДﾟ) ごめんなさいが、きこえない (えーん!)
Huh? (ﾟДﾟ) I can't hear your apology! (Eh~!)
粛聖!ロリ神レクイエム☆
Purification! Loli-god Requiem☆
本当に気持ち悪い。
Truly disgusting.
冷凍うどんは常備してます！そうでしたっけ？
I always keep frozen udon on hand! Is that right?
やったー！しこくよー！
Yay! It's Shiko... Koyori!
ここはこよりだよ！博衣こよりです！
This is Koyori! I'm Hakui Koyori!
ハッシュタグこよりすけっちでリスナーさんOK！
Hashtag #Koyorisketch, listeners are good to go!
ここは…ここはどこですか？
Where... where is this?
やったー！こよりすけっちできる！
Yay! I can do Koyorisketch!
はい！せーの！
Ready, set, go!
女のガチトーク第4弾！
The girls' serious talk, part 4!
いぇーい！やったー！
Yay! Hooray!
4回目だ！4回目です！
It's the 4th time! It's our 4th time!
そして今回もなんとゲストがいます！やったー！
And this time, we even have a guest! Yay!
やったー！いらっしゃーい！
Yay! Welcome!
いらっしゃい！いらっしゃい！
Welcome! Welcome!
本日はノエル先輩が遊びに来てくれました！よろしくお願いいたします！
Today, Noel-senpai came to hang out with us! Thanks for having us!
よろしくお願いします！
Thank you for having me!
ほんなら、ちょっと自己紹介がてら今日の意気込みなど聞いてみましょうか。らみたん！
Well then, let's hear a bit of self-introduction and your enthusiasm. Lamy-tan!
ホロライブ5期生の顔が肝臓、雪花ラミィです！今日もどんな相談が来てるのか楽しみです！
I'm Yukisaki Lamy, the liver of Hololive 5th gen! I'm excited to see what consultations we got today!
よろしくお願いします！
Looking forward to it!
そして、その…その…脳の方、博衣こよりだよ！
And, um... um, the brain department, Hakui Koyori!
え、毎回どんどんマシュマロが増えている気がします。
Um, I feel like the marshmallows keep increasing every time.
みんなは、そう、嬉しいことだ！
Everyone... yeah, that's so wonderful!
ねえ、本当嬉しくて、あとはみんなが結構ね、恋愛してるんだなとホクホクしております。
Right, I'm really happy, and seeing everyone so in love warms my heart.
え、今日もありがとうございます！よろしくお願いします！
Um, thank you today as well! Looking forward to it!
えーそしてゲストのノエル先輩！どうですかこの番組！
And guest Noel-senpai! How do you like this show?
はーい！よろしくお願いします！
Yes! Thank you!
えー、皆さんこんばんは！ホロライブ3期生の白銀ノエルです。
Good evening everyone! I'm Shirogane Noel from Hololive 3rd gen.
いや、ずっとね、ちょっと興味があり、団長の小余子ちゃんとかにね、その
I've always been a bit interested, and I asked Koyoko-chan and others...
いや、あれってゲストってどんな感じのって
"Wait, what are guests even like?"
チラチラ、いつでも空いてますよみたいなね、そういう感じで
like "I'm always free!" hinting around like that.
ちょっとカマチョームーブをしたら、なんと今回お呼びいただきました！ありがとうございます！
So after making those attention-seeking moves, I was finally invited this time! Thank you!
おめでとうございます！
Congratulations!
嬉しい！ありがとうございます！嬉しい！
I'm so happy! Thank you so much! I'm so happy!
いや、この番組よく言ってるんですけど、とっても人を選ぶと思っておりまして
I always say on this show, but I think it really selects its guests carefully,
まあね、まあもちろん、存じ上げておりますけどね。
well, of course, I'm well aware of that.
その深い時間にするのにね、あのぴったりな深い番組になってるので、行きたいって言ってもらえるのですごい嬉しかったんです！今日はよろしくお願いします！
Since it's done at such a late hour, it's the perfect deep-night show, so I was super happy when you said you wanted to come! Thanks for having me!
お願いします！よろしくお願いします！
Thank you! Looking forward to it!
NGは、ない感じですかね？
Is there basically no NG topics?
いや、もうもちろん、NGなんてありま、本当！
Well, of course, there's no NG at all! Really?!
なにがあったの？
What happened?
ないの？
None?
ない。いや、うん。
None. Well, yeah.
まあ、ちょっとね、皆さんの、その恋愛がどんな感じなのかっていうのもそれ次第なところあるけど、団長的にはあの、NGないかなって思うじゃん。
Well, depending on what kind of love lives everyone has, but from a captain's perspective, I'd think there are no NGs.
その、やっぱこのね番組、団長もちょっと見させていただいておりまして、
Because I've been watching this show as the captain, too,
なんか団長だったらこんな気持ちだなとか、そういうのを想像しながらやってたので、今んとこNGは、えー。
and imagining how I would feel if I were the captain, so far my NGs are... um.
今んとこ、今んとこね。
Well, so far, so far anyway.
今日、今日ちょっとぶっ飛んでたらちょっとわかんないかも。
Today, if things get too wild today, I might not know.
ま、今日もね、これぐらいの感じかなと思いますので。
Well, I think it'll be about this vibe today.
はーい、よろしくお願いします！答えづらいときはね、「答えづらい」って言ってくださいはっきり。よろしくお願いします！
Alright, thanks for having me! If it's hard to answer, please clearly say "That's hard to answer." Thanks!
はい、無理強いは致しません！
Yes, we won't force you!
それでは見ていきましょう。じゃあ1個目、ジャブで、これ言っていいですか？ジャブというか、なんですが。
Let's take a look. First, as a jab, can I say this? Or rather, it's like this:
「こちゃんは『ノエル先輩』呼びですが、団長もっと打ち解けて愛称呼びしてほしいなーって、『マリリンシャ』並の愛称考えちゃいませんか？」という
"Koya-chan calls you 'Noel-senpai', but Captain wants you to get closer and call her by a nickname~ Won't you think of a nickname on par with 'Marinsha'?"
おお、いいじゃないですか！さっきの配信でも言ってくれていたのか？というメッセージが。
Oh, that's great! There was a message asking if you mentioned that in the earlier stream too.
そうなんだよね！なんか、あの、こよちゃんね、ずっと団長ノエル先輩って呼んでくれてて、
That's right! Koyo-chan has always called me Noel-senpai,
ちょっとそろそろね、先輩呼びじゃなくて、お近づきになりたいなっていう。でも嬉しい！
so I was thinking maybe it's about time we move past "senpai" and get closer. But I'm happy!
いいじゃないですか！色々遊んでるし、なんか呼び始めたら呼べそうな気がする。
That's nice! We hang out and stuff, so I feel like once I start calling you that, I could get used to it.
そう、慣れないかもだけど、やっぱ慣れなんだよね。時間かかるかもだけどね。
Right, you might not be used to it at first, but it's all about getting used to it. It might take some time though.
是非呼んでみて、なんだろうな。らみたんのえたん？なのかな？
Please try calling me something, I wonder what. Lamy-tan Noe-tan? Is that it?
らみたんのえたん？らみたんのえたん？
Lamy-tan Noe-tan? Lamy-tan Noe-tan?
のえ、のえ、のえるん？のえたん？のえ、のえるん、のえ、のえ、のえ、のえたんかな？
Noe, Noe, Noel-un? Noe-tan? Noe, Noel-un, Noe, Noe, Noe, Noe-tan maybe?
こちゃん、
"Ko-chan..."
呼ぼう、呼べた、呼べたんだよね？
"Let's call her that. I managed to call her that, right?"
呼べたんだね
"You managed to call her that."
呼べたんだ、呼べたんだか
"You managed to, or rather..."
呼べたんだね、呼べたんだ
"You did, you managed to."
行こうか にゃ
"Shall we go?"
下がる方がね、下がる方がね
"Lowering it is better, lowering it is better."
ちょっとやっていきたいと思います今日は。やった、えらい、いいですね。
"We'll do a bit of that today. Yay, good job, that's great."
さらにちょっとやっとつけられそうになったところで、これこれが本当のジャブですね。
"Right when it seemed like we could finally add a bit more, this is the real jab."
男ひとりで「ちいかわ」の映画を観に行っても大丈夫でしょうか？
"Is it okay for a guy to go see the Chiikawa movie all by himself?"
周りから白い目で見られたりしないでしょうか？少し不安です。
"Won't people give him weird looks? I'm a bit worried."
でも、おっさんもセーレンちゃんやしまじろうに会いたいんです
"But this guy wants to see Seiren-chan and Shimajiro too."
というのが
"That's what..."
え、何、だめな理由ある？逆に。
"Wait, is there any reason why not? Quite the opposite."
ない、ない、むしろ、いいよね。だよね。かわいい。
"No, no, if anything, it's great. Right? So cute."
で、そうなんこれ、こういうのって結構配信でもすでに言ってるんですけど、それでも悩み大きいあのリスナーさんがいたので、何もう恥ずかしくないな。
"Yeah, exactly. I've actually talked about stuff like this on stream before, but since there was a listener with such a big worry, there's nothing to be embarrassed about at all."
そうなんだ。全然恥ずかしくないよね。
"Is that right? There's nothing to be embarrassed about."
2人ともちいかわ映画観に行ってるもんにゃん。
"Both of you went to see the Chiikawa movie, right?"
うん、行ったよ。男ひとりの客さん。
"Yeah, we went. There were solo male customers."
もういた、いた、いた。しかもグッズもいっぱいつけてる。
"There were, definitely. And they had lots of merch on."
分かる、分かる。全然平気だよ。
"I know, right? It's totally fine."
気にするなというのを伝えるために紹介しました。
"I introduced it to let you know not to worry about it."
はい。
"Yes."
しかも、第5弾発表されたからね。
"Besides, the 5th wave was just announced."
ええ、そうなんだ。だからメジャーアクセスね。
"Oh really? So that means major access."
全然行ってほしい、ゲットしてほしいですよね。
"You should definitely go and get it."
ぜひしまじろうをゲットして下さい、ぜひ。はい、ぜひぜひ。
"Please go get Shimajiro, definitely. Yes, please do."
それでは続いてこちら行きましょう。女の子からです。
"Now let's move on to the next one. This is from a girl."
3人は学生時代スクールメイクなどしてましたか？
"Did the three of you do school makeup when you were students?"
私はしたいのですがよくわからないので参考にしたいです。おすすめのコスメなどあれば聞きたい…おすすめコスメはなんこかきてました。女子が。
"I want to try it, but I don't really know how, so I want some references. If you have any recommended cosmetics..."
あお、そうなんだ。教えてくれてるみたい。嬉しいですね。へえ、ありがたいですね。
"Oh is that right? Looks like they're teaching us. That's nice. How appreciated."
知ってた？スクールメイク。スクールメイク？
"Did you know about it? School makeup. School makeup?"
なんか薄メイクみたいな、ナチュラルメイク。
"Like light makeup, natural makeup."
どうなんだろう、学校行くときにメイクなのか？あとは学生時代にメイクってしてた？
"I wonder, is it makeup for going to school? Also, did you wear makeup during your student days?"
してた
"I did."
え？
"Eh?"
してた
"I did."
え、学校行くときも？してた？してた。すごーい！してたんだ。
"Eh, even when going to school? You did? Wow, you did!"
2人はしてなかった？
"The two of you didn't?"
学校行くときはしてなくて、お出かけの時にちょっと身を身も手入れしてた。
"I didn't when going to school, but when going out I'd take a little care of myself."
あー、なるほどなるほど。のえちゃんは？
"Ah, I see, I see. What about you, Noe-chan?"
のえ、のえちゃんは？のえ、あ、のえ、のえはね、あの…
"Noe, Noe-chan? Noe, ah, Noe, Noe was, um..."
いや、でもどうだ、そのスクールメイク…
"Well, but how was it, that school makeup..."
学生時代から、高校とかってことだよね？あ、そうそうそうそう。
"From student days, like high school right? Ah, yes yes yes."
ええ！なんかね、興味はあったけどしてなかったかな、なんか厳しかった。
"Ehh! I mean, I was interested, but I didn't do it. It was kind of strict."
あお、学校が、学校が厳しくて…
"Ah, the school, the school was strict..."
なんかしてる子はいたんよ。でもすぐ怒られちゃって、
"Some girls did it, but they'd get scolded right away,"
それを横目で見て、あ、厳しいなって。
"so seeing that out of the corner of my eye, I thought, 'Man, that's strict.'"
で、まだ早いかって思って、あ、そんな感じだった。
"And thought it was still too early for me. That was about it."
正しいと思うけどな。校則はそれぞれあるもんで。
"I think that's right though. School rules vary for each place."
お出かけの時もしてなかった？
"Did you not do it when going out either?"
お出かけの時はね、ちょっとあの見よう見まねでプチプラあるじゃん？
"When going out, you know, I tried imitating things with affordable drugstore brands."
400円とか500円のさ、クレームチークとか買って、チークだけ塗ってた黒歴史がある。
"I bought 400 or 500 yen cream blush or something and only put on blush. Such a cringe dark past."
え、クリームチークは無いだろ。でも確かに今思うと、やっぱさ、トータル大事じゃん？メイクの。
"Eh, cream blush isn't bad. But thinking back now, the overall look is what's important in makeup, right?"
そういうのを気にせず、口紅にだけとかさ、チークだけっていうのなんか本当に下手くそだった思い出があるから、ちょっとね、そこは恥ずかしいなって感じだけど。
"Without caring about that, just putting on lipstick or just blush... I remember being really clumsy at it, so looking back, it's kind of embarrassing."
チークオンリーはなかなか見んかもね。
"You don't really see just blush very often."
結構知ってたんだ。
"You knew quite a bit."
のえ、のえちゃんはなんかばっちりしてそうだな。
"Noe-chan looks like she'd do full makeup."
ばっちりね？
"Full makeup?"
ラミーはしてたね。なんか結構コスメ好きだったから。
"Lamy did. Because I really liked cosmetics."
別に誰に見られるわけでもなく、スクールメイクしてましたね。
"Without anyone even seeing, I did school makeup."
ええ、なんか、コツというかさ、スクールだからこそみたいなやり方とかあった？
"Ehh, did you have any tips, like techniques specifically for school?"
あ、でも、アイラインめちゃ濃く引いちゃうとさ、バレちゃうじゃん？あ、確かに。バレないようにやってたんだ、ラミーも。一応ね。
"Well, if you draw eyeliner too dark, you'd get caught, right? Ah, true. So you tried not to get caught, Lamy. Just in case."
一応バレないようにというか、薄めに、薄めにやってた。
"Well, not to get caught, I mean, I kept it light, nice and light."
でもなんか結構いろいろ眉とかも整えてたし
Well, but you know, we used to trim our eyebrows and stuff.
ああ、確かに
Ah, true.
眉毛整え
Eyebrow trimming...
眉毛ね
Eyebrows, right.
大事！
Important!
大事だよね
So important, right?
うんうんうんうん
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
そう、やっぱ眉毛はね、顔の印象だいぶ変わりますからね。うんうんうん。
Yeah, eyebrows really change the impression of your face. Yeah.
うん、だからだいぶナチュラルメイク、キャンメイクとかも使ってたよ。
So, I used pretty natural makeup, like Canmake.
あのプチプラの
That affordable brand...
キャンメイクですようやっぱ。
Canmake is the best, after all.
キャンメイクだよね。うん。
It's Canmake, right? Yeah.
プチプラだね。
Affordable, right.
キャンメイク今も使ってて結構
Canmake is still used by a lot of people, and...
お、かわいいしパッケージがね。
Oh, and it's cute, right, the packaging?
そう、かわいい、安い、しかも結構質が高いと
Yeah, it's cute, cheap, and I think the quality is pretty high!
思っている。
I think so.
うん。
Yeah.
めっちゃいいのが、そのこの価格だけど、チークの塗りとかもすごい綺麗に出るし
It's really good that even at that price, you can apply cheek makeup really cleanly.
うん。
Yeah.
そうそう。なんかね、お勧めのコスメすごい好きな男友達がいるんだけど
Yeah, yeah. One of my friends who loves cosmetics uses Canmake a lot.
その子も
And that friend...
キャンメイク結構取り入れてて
Also incorporates Canmake a lot.
なんか高いお金にこう個室しなくても全然素敵なねメイクできるなってお勧めしたかったんです。
Like, even without using high-end products, you can do really wonderful makeup, so I'd love to recommend it.
そうなんだよね。
Yeah, that's true.
お勧めだね。
Definitely recommend it.
ていうか今ね、結構100均とかでもさ、あのメイクグッズって言ってるじゃないですか。
And you know, nowadays even places like Seria sell makeup goods, right?
確かにある。
That's true.
あれもなんか結構普通に使えるんよ。
Those can actually be used quite normally too.
え、そうなんだ！
Oh, is that so?
そっそっそっそっそ。
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
よく使ったことなかったから、おすすめとかある？
Have you ever used them? Any recommendations?
あ、でもアイライナーとかは全然発色もいいし、落ちにくいし。
Ah, but eyeliners and stuff have really good colors and are easy to apply!
あ、そうなんだ！すごい！
Oh, is that so? Amazing!
そう、全然使えるよ、めちゃいいよ。
Yeah, they're totally usable, really good.
学生だとやっぱね、高いからね、メイク道具も。一つずつさ、なんか月1ぐらいの感じになるじゃん、1個ずつ。
As a student, you know, makeup tools are expensive, right? Especially when buying item by item every month...
そうするとやっぱ100均うれしいよな。
So buying them at 100-yen shops makes you so happy.
100均ありがたいよね。
100-yen shops are really helpful.
うんうん、ぜひ参考にしてみてくだいさーい。
So please definitely use this as a reference!
はーい！
Yes!
はい、では次ちょっと男子からね、いってみましょうかね。
Now, let's move on to the next one, which is from the boys' perspective, maybe?
たぶん男子。
Probably...
えー、美女3人のフェチが知りたいです！！という。うわ、フェチ！フェチ！
"We want to know the fetishes of the three beautiful women!!" What is this? Fetishes! Fetishes!
フェチか。
Fetishes...
何フェチ、ある？
What kind of fetishes are there?
今ちょっと考えてる。
I'm thinking about it now.
もう考えてる。
I'm thinking.
でさ、ねえ、Lamy結構ねやっぱちょっと汗の匂いかもしれないな。
Well, you know, Lamy might have a bit of a sweat scent maybe?
え、匂い？
Ah, sweat?
そう、だよね、言ってたちゅーかうん。
That's what you were saying earlier.
そう、ちょっとやっぱみんな、今さ、ちょっと露出が激しいじゃないですか、今。うんうんうんうん。
Yeah, because everyone's exposure is so intense right now, you know?
やっぱでもなんかちょっと汗かいてそうなところの匂い嗅ぎたいもんね。
Yeah, but you know, I want to smell the sweat where it feels like they've been sweating!
えー！
Eh?!
かがせたくないよ！
You don't want people to smell yours!
そうなんだ。
That's right, exactly.
いや、かがせたくないよ！
You don't want people to smell yours!
汗は汗やで。
Sweat is sweat, though!
そうだな。
That's true.
そう、これ前も、もしかしたら取り扱ったかもしれない。コヨエは、こう言ったときも言ってた気がしますね。
Well, before this, maybe I talked about it too. Koyoe? I think I mentioned it then too.
あ、コヨエなんだ。
Ah, Koyoe, right?
うん、コヨエが。
Yeah, Koyoe.
やっぱなんか声優さんとか好きだったから、子供の頃から。あ、この人の声はこんな感じなんだな、みたいなのをちょっとまず気にしてしまうところありますね。
Well, I like voice actors and stuff since I was a child, so I'm always like, "Oh, this person's voice sounds like this," first.
のえる先輩。
Ah, Noel-senpai?
匂った？
Did you smell it?
匂った！
I smelled it!
匂った。
Smelled it.
匂った！
Smelled it!
匂ったです。
Smelled it, yeah.
匂えた。
Smelled it.
匂えたは
Smelled it is...
じゃあ、手かも。
What about hands?
手？
Hands?
お、手？
Oh, hands?
手ってどういう手が良いかというと
Hands, what kind of hands are good?
むちむちな手が好き。むち、あ、赤ちゃんみたいな。
I like rugged, rugged hands, like a baby's.
赤ちゃんみたいな！
Ah, like a baby!
赤ちゃんみたいな手が大きい。
Baby-like hands are big.
えー！
Eh?
意外！
Really?
意外、なんかさ、触ったら気持ちよさそう、とかそういう感じ？
Really? Unexpectedly, if you touch them, you feel cozy, or something like that?
まあそうだし、なんかこう見た目あ狙いもかわいい、なと思って。
Well, that's true, and also, visually they look cute, I think.
で、なんかやっぱさ、手とかって、骨格とかなんかな、骨格でさ、その見た目には全然細いのに
And you know, like hands, what about skeletons? Like bone structure, and...
手だけさ、ちょっとむちむちしてる女の子とかいるじゃん。
Hands alone are a bit chubby, you know, there are girls like that!
確かにかか。
True, true, true.
そう、なんかそういう子に憧れるんだよね。長髪散歩...
Yeah, you kind of yearn for that kind of thing. Like elder brother's...
ま、ちょっと今画面にはね、あの、映ってないけど
Well, right now on screen, we don't have it, but...
手が結構やっぱり、なんか骨、骨がちょっと、こう張ってるんだよね。
Hands, quite often, you know, bones, bones are a bit protruding, right?
これがちょっとコンプレックスで、え、そうなんだ。
That's a bit of a complex for me, and...
そう、なんか丸みがあるお手々は、ずーっと憧れてるの。
Yeah, like having round hands is something I've always yearned for.
えー、そうなの！知らなかったん。
Eh, really? I didn't know that!
そうだよ。
That's right.
だからクリームパンみたいな手とかもうだいぶ好き、握りたくなるかもね。
Like cream-pan-like hands, I just love them, make you want to hold them!
そう。
Yeah.
へえー！
Right.
なんか今でもコメント欄に「きらよしかげって言われてて」
Like, someone in the comments is saying, "I'll make Lamy-san cut her hair!"
いやいやそんな
No, no, that's...
切ったり、そこまでじゃない。そこまでじゃない。怖い、怖い。
Cutting it is going too far, like Kira Yoshikage! That's too far!
ちょっと気になっちゃうな、というところですかね。
So you end up caring about it, you could say.
そうですね、もうフェチですよ。
Yeah, exactly. It's a fetish.
あ、そうなんだ。
Oh, I see.
なるほど。
Got it.
では、もう一個ちょっと、のえる先輩に聞きたい。我々前回話してるやつなんだけど。
Then, let's ask Noel-senpai about another one. We talked about this before, right?
あ、のえたんね！話した！
Ah, we talked about it!
あ、のえたん、あざす！ありがとうございます！
Oh, Noel-senpai, thank you very much!
相手に対して冷める瞬間があるとしたら
If there's a moment when your feelings suddenly cool down,
どんな瞬間ですか？よろしくお願いします！！
what kind of moment is that? Looking forward to it!
あー 聞きたいですね
Ah, I'd love to hear that.
聞きたい！
I wanna hear it!
なんか冷めるかっていうか、なんか前回は
Like, rather than losing feelings... last time,
なんか100年の恋も冷めるみたいなのって何？みたいな
we talked about what a "hundred-year romance cooling" means.
話をしていいて、
While we were talking about that,
なんかこよりはなんかその、あの店員さんとかに怒っちゃうとかがあると同じしてただね
you were saying getting mad at restaurant staff is a turn-off, right?
いや、それもちろん知っておりますよ
Well, of course I know that!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
見てくださってありがとうございます！
Thank you for tuning in!
え、男女その配信を見ながら、自分だったらなんだろうって
Watching the stream as a guy, I wondered what I would think.
ちょっと、思ってたんだけど
I was thinking about that, but...
えー なんか、そうだな、嘘、嘘かな、嘘つかれた時とか
Um... maybe lying? When someone lies to you.
でもうそってさ、いんなる嘘が、あるじゃんか、で
But there are different kinds of lies, right?
なんかそうゆう、嘘でも、優しい嘘ならいいと思うんだけど、なんか見栄を張るような嘘だと冷めちゃうかも。
Gentle lies are fine, but lies to save face are a turn-off.
ええ 見栄を張るような嘘って例えば？
What's a lie to save face? For example?
俺、貯蓄500億あるとか
"I have 50 billion yen in savings," or something.
あーなるほどね、いやそれは、それはギャグだからいいんだけど
Ah, I see. Well, that's a joke so it's fine, but...
いや、いいんだ。
Wait, it's fine?
500、500億はいいのね？500億はね？
50 billion is fine? 50 billion?
確かに500億はね、500億はね、だからまあ、そう、なんかちょっとした見栄
True, 50 billion... so like, a little bit of showing off...
なんか自分をよく見せようっていうのは、まあ背伸びすたくらいだったらいいかもだけど
Trying to make yourself look better by stretching a bit might be fine,
なんかちょっと、いや、いやかもな。でも嘘でやってみてもねみたいな感じだよね。
but maybe not. Doing it with lies... that kind of vibe.
団長はね、弱いところを見たい。
Dancho wants to see vulnerability.
なんかそうやって嘘をついてまで、強く言おうみたいなのはちょっと嫌だなあって。
Putting up a strong front with lies is kind of a turn-off.
もっとね、弱いね、本当のところを見せてほしいんだよね、団長はね。
She wants to see the genuinely weak, real side of you.
そう、団長ね、幼少化したおじさんが好きなんだからね！幼児も好きだもんね。そう。
Dancho likes middle-aged men with a childish side! She loves childhood friends too.
いや、あのなんか、あのキャラクターで言う、幼児も好き、幼児って、あれちょっとちょっとちょっと、すっかりのノエルだと思ったんですけど。
In terms of characters, I like childhood friends too... wait, I thought it was Noel.
まあ、まあ、まあ、なんか、やっぱり
Well, after all...
その、ま、バキのね、バキっていう作品の、あのドリアンっていうキャラがいるんだけど、その人がね、その幼少化したおじいちゃん
In Baki, there's a character named Dorian, and that guy is an aged-down old man...
幼児化したおじいちゃんなんだ。そう。
He's an aged-down old man. Right.
それが本当にタイプで、なんか嘘ついて欲しくないな。ありのままで
That's really my type, so I don't want them to lie. Just staying as they are...
幼児化するんや。いや、ちょっと調べたんだよね。
They age down? Well, I looked it up.
あ、調べた。そう、これ幼児化するキャンディ求めますから。
That's right, because they want candy that makes them act like babies.
あ、なるほど。あ、僕をたくさん欲しいて言ってるキャンディが。そうなのよ。
Ah, I see. "I want lots of me" candy.
かわいいんだよ。キャンディ、キャンディ
It's so cute. Candy, candy...
キャンディおじさんだからね。ね、キャンディとかいらねえしとか言わないでほしいっていうことですかね？
So you don't want them to say "I don't need candy" or stuff like that?
そうだね。
That's right.
強がんなくて本当はキャンディが欲しいのに、やキャンディとかそんな甘いもん食えねえしとか
Even though they really want candy and put up a front saying "I can't eat sweets,"
言わないでいいからね！あ、そのままのままでいいよ、ね？て甘えがして下さい。
you don't have to say that! Just stay as you are, okay? Let me spoil you.
いや、わかるわ。
Man, I totally get it.
萌えに甘いられるの、最高やんけ！
Being pampered by someone moe is the absolute best!
幼児化していいなら、するがね、するけど。
If it's okay to act like a baby, I mean, I would... but...
いいんですか？しかもそれで愛してもらえるの、最高すぎるの。ねえ、最高すぎる。
Is that okay? And having you love me for it is just too amazing.
お世話したい。
I want to take care of you.
え、じゃあちょっと、これは幼児化に入るのかという質問なんですけど。
Here's a question: does this count as infantilization?
はい。え、正直、下ネタ言う男子はたませんか？
Yes. Honestly, can guys who make dirty jokes not be popular?
という、どのレベルの？え、わかんない。
That's... what level? I don't know.
それはちょっと想像と、あのここまでならオッケーとかあったら、ぜひそこも聞きたいんですけど。
If there's a limit like "up to here is okay," I'd love to hear that.
下ネタ言う男子一発。下ネタに緩くないから、ねねぐらいのだったら全然、君なんないけど、小学生男子みたいなの。
Guys who make dirty jokes right off the bat. Like elementary school boys.
え、持てるか持てないかで考えると、どう思いますか？
Thinking in terms of popularity, what do you think?
持てないんじゃない？
They probably aren't popular, right?
いや、なんかさ、モカシーの問題じゃない？
Well, isn't it a question of decency?
なんかその、女の子の前でさ、わざわざ下ネタを言わなくても良くないかってなる。
Do you really need to go out of your way to make dirty jokes in front of girls?
そうやんな。そうだよな。やっぱりそういう話っていうのはさ
That's right. After all, those kinds of topics...
関係値とかが大事で。
...the relationship status matters.
そこまでの関係値に行っでる、てことは もう下ネタ抜きで持ててる気がするから。
Reaching that level means you probably have charm without dirty jokes.
だから下ネタでもて るってことは確かになくない？
So saying dirty jokes to get popular... isn't that rare?
逆説ね。下ネタ言って持てるはない。ない！確かにない。
Making dirty jokes doesn't make you popular. No way! Definitely not.
なんか友達止まりになっちゃいそうな感じがする
It feels like it's gonna end up just being friends.
ああ まあ うん
Ah, well... yeah.
好きな男の子が下ネタめっちゃ言ってたらでもちょっとやだ、なあ
If the guy you like is constantly making crude jokes, I'd probably be turned off.
確かに
True.
なんかちょっとちょっとげんめつすることもあるかもね、下ネタの質によっては。うん、うん。
You might actually get a bit disillusioned depending on the quality of the crude jokes... Yeah, yeah.
え、でもこの質問が来るってことは、言いながらモテたいてことなのかな？
Wait, but if this question is coming in, does that mean they want to say them and still be popular?
「俺は下ネタを言いたいんだ！」って言う、その欲望！
"I want to make crude jokes!"—that desire!
欲望、それでモテたら嬉しいなみたいな。
That desire, like, "And if I'm popular anyway, I'd be happy."
だからいっちゃうタイプだから、このまま生きててもうモテるならこのままで生きるがこれでモテないならやめようかなみたいなのがあるんだよね。
So since that's just the type they are, they're probably thinking, "If I can live life like this and still be popular, I'll keep doing it, but if not, maybe I'll quit."
いやこれちょっとデカイぞ、この子今後モテるかモテないかちょっと左右するかもしれない。
Wait, this is kinda huge. Whether this kid gets popular in the future might depend on this.
マジで言っとかないと、下ネタはたぶんモテないぞ。
Seriously, if someone doesn't tell him, making crude jokes probably won't get him any girls.
あ、そうね、モテる要素がないかもね。
Ah, right. There might be zero appeal there.
確かに確かに。で、モテたいならちょっと控えたほうが。男子だけの話題でね。
True. So if he wants to be popular, he should probably hold back... talking only among guys, you know.
言って発散したりしたらいいんじゃないですかね？
Expressing it and letting off steam like that would be fine, wouldn't it?
はい。
Yeah.
それができるのはちょっと、全然関係ない話していいよ。
Wait, that can... We can talk about something completely unrelated, right?
あのさ、この間さ、あの友達とね、ご飯に行ったんですよ。
So recently, you know, I went out to eat with a friend.
うん。そしたらそこノ裏にいた、後ろにいた、あの、男の子の4人組ぐらいがいたんですけど。
Yeah. And behind us, like right behind us, there was a group of about four guys.
え、げ、下ネタ言ってて！
And, man, they were making super crude jokes!
きまず！
Awkward!
え、もうずっと、最初から最後まで下ネタ言ってて！
They were literally making crude jokes from start to finish!
マジか。
Seriously?
まあでも、なんだろう、こっちまで聞こえちゃうのはあれだけど、でもね、男の子の場ってね、そうそうそう。
Well, I mean, it's one thing that we could hear it over here, but guys in their own space are totally like that, right?
男子ってやっぱ、そういうもんなのかね、その我々は知らないじゃん。
Do guys really just act like that? We wouldn't know, right?
男子だけの集まりを。みんな、そう、そうなの？みんなは。
An all-boys gathering. Is everyone... is it really like that for everyone?
そうなの、聞きたい。
Is it? I wanna know.
コメントの「みんなはね」ちょっと教えてって言ってる人もいるから。
Some people in the chat are saying, "Hey, everyone, tell us!"
ああ。聞かないであげて。
Ah. Don't ask them.
聞こえてきちゃったんだもん、だって。
We just happened to overhear it, you know.
あ、そうね。聞こえてきちゃったんだもん、だって。
Ah, right. You guys just heard it.
それはね、そっちのボリュームの問題だからね。
Well, that's just a matter of their volume, though.
あ、人による、言わないよ。学生はそうかも。だそう。
Ah, depends on the person, they don't say it. Students might, though. Apparently.
あ、でもそう、学生感っぽかった。ちょっと、なるほどな。
Ah, but yeah, it felt very student-like. Makes sense.
ちょっと、まだ若さ抜けてない。まだ青春なのかな、まだね。でもそういう夜結構聞いちゃうかも。
Still not quite over their youth. Still in their youth phase, maybe. But you hear that kind of stuff pretty often at night.
こういう話するんだ。
So they talk about stuff like this.
私女子校だったからさ、わかんないね、本当に、学生の男の子たちって何を考えてるのか。
I went to an all-girls school, so I really have no idea what male students are thinking.
分析しちゃうんだ。なるほど。
You analyze them. I see.
ちなみにノエたん、あの、何校、何校というか、共学女子校どっちでしたっけ？
By the way, Noetan, what kind of school did you go to? Was it co-ed or an all-girls school?
ええとね、高校まで共学で、大学で女子だった。
Um, co-ed up until high school, and then an all-girls university.
あ、結構珍しいタイプ。
Oh, that's a pretty rare type.
なるほど、じゃあどっちも知ってるみたいな。
I see, so you know both sides.
そうだね、そうね。
That's right, yeah.
一応、まあ私するけども、まあでも男子も気になるね、なんか、話し、聞きます、ね、聞いちゃいます。
Well, I mean, I do, but guys are still interesting, you know... I listen and end up hearing about it.
じゃあそんな、共学と共学女子校と女子校の3人それぞれがどうなのかという。
So, regarding how the three of us from co-ed, co-ed/girls' school, and all-girls school feel...
こちら、えっと、なんだ？
Here... um, what's this?
3人に恋愛の2択についてお聞きしたいです。好きな人恋愛対象に刺激と安心どちらを求めますか？
"I'd like to ask the three of you about a choice in romance. Between stimulation and peace of mind, which do you seek in your romantic interest?"
おませぶりの言動なので毎回ドキドキさせてくる方か、一緒にいて落ち着き全体でいられる方どちらを重視されるでしょうか？
"Do you prioritize someone who makes your heart pound every time with precocious words and actions, or someone you can feel entirely at ease with?"
私は安心タイプで好きだよとかは伝えられるのですが、ドラマのようにドキドキさせるような言動は恥ずかしくてもなかなかできません。女の子はどっちの方が嬉しいですかということなので、ちょっとこれせーので
"I'm the peace-of-mind type. I can say things like "I like you," but doing things like in dramas to make someone's heart race is embarrassing and hard for me. Which do you girls prefer? So let's do a "Ready, set...""
刺激か、安心か、どっちか答えてみたいなと思います。いいよ。
and answer either "stimulation" or "peace of mind." Ready?
はい。
Yep.
せーの！
Ready, set!
安心！安心！
Peace of mind! Peace of mind!
おお！
Oh!
揃った！
It matched!
おお、揃ったね！
Oh, it matched!
安心が。
Peace of mind...
ここは揃いましたね。
We matched here.
その、外の心はラミたん。
And outside of that, Lamy-tan?
あ、ラミ？
Oh, Lamy?
え、刺激って、その、なんか今書いてあるのは「おませぶりの言動なので毎回ドキドキさせてくる」って書いてあるけど
Wait, "stimulation," um, what's written here is "doing precocious actions so it makes your heart race every time,"
そんなおませぶりの言動されたら、ラミもう困るんだけど！え、それ何？どういう意味？
If someone did precocious things like that, Lamy would be in trouble! Wait, what is that? What does that mean?
確かにね。何、ラミのこと好きじゃないってこと？どういうこと？どういうことすんの？
True. What, does that mean they don't like Lamy? What does that mean? What kind of stuff are they doing?
そうだね、それは違うよ。なんちゃって、なんちゃって。
Right, that's not it. Just kidding, just kidding.
絶対安心の方がいいの？
Is peace of mind definitely better?
え、のえちゃんはどうですか？
Um, how about you, Noe-chan?
いや、なんか人生ってさ、生きるって大変やん。それなのに刺激なんていらんです。
Well, you know, life... living is hard enough. Despite that, I don't need stimulation.
安心が欲しい！やっぱり！
I want peace of mind! Seriously!
優しさが欲しいでしょ、安心よ。
I want kindness, peace of mind.
それはわかるわ。
I totally get that.
めちゃくちゃ。
Extremely.
いやなんか、こうずっと一緒にいるっていう前提で考えたくて
Well, I kinda want to think under the premise of being together forever...
この恋愛というものを
This thing called romance...
その、あ、何、それ、それって24時間一緒にいるってこと？どういうこと？
Like, wait, what, does that mean being together 24 hours? What does that mean?
っていうか、もう、なんだろう、付き合って本当に行けるならゴールのその結婚、そして生涯を最後までみたいなぐらいのところを
I mean, if things work out, you'd want to go all the way to marriage and a lifelong commitment until the very end,
墓場までね。
until the grave, yeah.
そう、墓場までみたいなことを考えて、恋愛というものを考えたときに、
Yeah, thinking about something like "until the grave," when you think about romance,
なんか、安心が、もう、大事すぎない？
isn't peace of mind way too important?
ずっと癒やされてね、安心し て、こう、なんかホッとする家庭ででありたいと思うから、
You want a home where you're constantly healed, feel at ease, and can just relax, right?
だから、なんか、別に刺激いらんなってなるの。うん。
So because of that, you end up thinking, "I don't really need any excitement." Yeah.
まあ、そうだね、長く一緒にいること考えたら、刺激って逆になんか困るかもな。
Well, that's true. If you think about being together for a long time, excitement might actually be troublesome.
しかもさ、刺激を求めてるってことは、刺激ってさ、なんか慣れてくじゃんか。色んな絡みがあったりそう。
And besides, seeking excitement means getting used to it, right? With all sorts of twists and turns.
だからこの場合の刺激っていうのは最終的にどこまで行く、なんかちょっと怖いね。
So in this case, how far does that "excitement" ultimately go? It's kind of scary.
確かに。怖い。
True. Scary.
そう、長く見たときに、なんかちょっとした刺激じゃもう全然反応をしなくなっちゃいそう。うん。
Yeah, when you look at it long-term, minor excitement wouldn't get any reaction at all anymore. Yeah.
SMに発展していってしまうのか、大丈夫そう？そっちに行く？
Would it develop into SM? Are you okay? Is it going that way?
うん、まあなんか刺激とかは最初の3回ぐらいまででいいんじゃないかなみたいな
Yeah, well, I feel like excitement is probably enough for just the first three times or so,
感じよね、付き合う前とかにそういうドキドキ感があればいいんじゃない？勝手にドキドキするだろうしね。
don't you think? Like having that heart-pounding feeling before dating. Your heart would just race on its own anyway.
いやもう、勝手にやめて。二人でね？そうそうそう。
Oh, stop it. Just the two of you? Yeah, yeah.
はい、ということで、もう、わかんないですけど、多くの女の子は安心なんじゃないかなという。はい。
Right, so, I don't really know, but probably most girls just want peace of mind, right? Yes.
そうですね、そうですね。
That's right, exactly.
で、ちょっと恋愛とはまた別なところなんです けれど も、あの、脱毛しようか迷っています。過去男子は、あ、待って、早い、早い、おーい。女性から見て毛があるのとないのとでは結構印象変わってくるのでしょうか？
And on a slightly different note from romance, I'm debating whether to get hair removal. Wait, past guys... wait, too fast, hey! From a woman's perspective, does having body hair vs. not change the impression quite a bit?
え、白いの？
Eh? White?
え、もう絶対ヒゲ脱毛とかしたほ方がよくない？だって
Eh, wouldn't it be way better to get beard hair removal? Because...
いや、なんかさ、毎朝毎朝さ、剃ってるんでしょ？
I mean, like, you're shaving every single morning, right?
あ、確かに。うんうん。
Ah, true. Yeah, yeah.
だし、なんかこうゆう、歯がさ、やっぱ肌にあたると刺激になってさ、そこが荒れちゃったりとかするわけじゃないですか。あ、そうなの？そうなんだ。へえーって。
And teeth hitting the skin causes irritation, and that part can get irritated or chafed, right? Oh, is that so? Really? Huh.
そういうの考えると、もう絶対ヒゲ脱毛なんてラミが男性だったらまずまっさきにやる。
Thinking about that, if Lamy were a guy, I'd definitely get beard hair removal first thing.
あ、確かに。
Ah, true.
あの、ヒゲ脱毛ね、生やしたい人はそのままで生やしてくださればいいけど、剃ってる人はね。
Well, if you want to grow a beard, you can keep it, but for those who shave...
楽になると思うけど。
it'd be easier, I think.
ダンズさんは、そこまでって感じ？
For Danchou, is it not that far?
なんか、団長は、あんまり、その、ラミィはさ、その、その人のこと思って言ってくれてるじゃんか。あ、そういえば視点があるんだって思ったけど。
Lamy, you're saying this out of consideration for that person, right? I thought, "Oh, so there's that perspective."
団長ちょっとね、あの、自分の好みで言うと、なんか本当にどっちでもよくて、
For Danchou, um, in terms of my own preference, honestly either way is fine,
え、なんかさ、け、け、毛があったときにね、その、やっぱ毛ってさ、意味があるところに入るわけじゃん。あー、ま、守るためにね。うん。
but like, when there's hair, hair is in places for a reason, right? Ah, to protect you. Yeah.
毛深い人はその分体をなんか守んなきゃいけないのかなと思って。
I thought that hairy people probably have to protect their bodies more because of that.
はあ、だからストーリーなんだね。
Huh, so it's a story.
なんか、なんか、すごい熊さんみたいだなっていう感じで、う、なんかかわいいなって。
It's like, they're like a cute bear or something, I feel. Cute, right?
うん、いや、でも、なんか本当にね、脱毛しようかしないかで言うなら、脱毛しようか迷ってんだとしたらしたほうがいいと思う。
Yeah, but really, if you're wondering whether to get hair removal or not, if you're hesitating, I think you should do it.
ああ、確かに、確かに。うん。
Ah, true, true. Yeah.
そう、なんか女子だ、あの、女子から見て、なんか毛があったほうがいいとかないほうがとかは、色々、人それぞれだと思うけど。
Yeah, like, whether girls prefer having hair or not, I think it varies from person to person,
やっぱ自分自身だと思うな。しかも脱毛痛い。
but I think it's about yourself. Plus, hair removal hurts.
そうね。そうね、お金もかかりますし。
That's right. It costs money, too.
から、その、周りからどう見られるかよりも、自分自身がやって、なんかこう、過ごしやすいかでやったほうが後悔もないと思うので、
So rather than how people around you view it, doing it based on what makes it easier for you to live will result in no regrets,
あ、確かに、そうか、もう確かにね、うん。
ah, true, that's right, yeah.
まあね、そういう感じで、団長は。うん。
Well, yeah, that's how Danchou feels.
でもね、毛がある人を見て、毛があるな、やだなって思うことはないよね。
But you know, when you see someone with hair, you don't think, "They have hair, gross," right?
なんか、うん、そんな、毛深い人を見たことがない。
Like, yeah, I've never really seen someone excessively hairy.
私たちだって、その、道行く人でしかないから。
Because we're just people passing by in the street,
そこでする考えること、
so we don't think about stuff like that there.
うん、その脱毛したからいいとか、してないからいいとか、そういうその印象の変化っていうのは、なんか無いのかないうような。
Yeah, whether they got hair removal or not, that kind of change in impression isn't really there.
感じ。あ、剃る人なんだな。あ、毛、そのままの人なんだな、それだけって感じがする。
Like, "Oh, they're the type to shave." "Oh, they're the type who keeps their hair." Just that impression.
うん、なんか、本当にスタイルだよね、その人の生きざまというか。
Yeah, it really comes down to style, right? Like their way of life or personal aesthetic.
ってことで、あんまり気にしたことないね。
So I've never really worried about that.
うん。
Yeah.
ま、でもなんか、ヒゲを、そう、脱毛したいと、迷ってるならしたほうがいいっていう、ラミたんの熱い
But you know, Lamy-tan's super passionate that if you're hesitating about getting beard hair removal, you should just do it—
熱い！ 絶対だって、ねえ、困ってる
Passionate! Absolutely, I mean, if you're struggling—
そうだもんね、きっとその、やっぱ、毎回剃ったりとかね、そう、肌荒れしたりとか
That's right, I'm sure you have to shave every time, and it causes skin irritation...
圧倒的に自分がやっぱ脱毛してよかったって感じているから
You feel overwhelmingly glad that you got hair removal yourself.
ああ、なるほどね。
Ah, I see.
っていうのもあるかない？ 脱毛いいだかなってね。
So there's that aspect too. Hair removal is great, you know.
確かにね。脱毛いいははあるな。うんね。
True. Hair removal is definitely great. Yeah.
意外とね、あの、すごいタイトことか、麻酔とかやれる？
Surprisingly, you know, can you do tight spots or anesthesia?
髭ってどうなんだろう？分かんないけど。分かんないけど。
What about beards? How does it work? I don't know.
ねえ、どうなんだろうか。調べてみてもいいのではないかとうかがおもいます。
I don't know, but I wonder how it is. We could try looking it up, don't you think?
おもいます！
We think so!
はい！ さあ、では
Yes! Now then,
続きまして、ちょっと変なのおいていいですか？
moving on, can we bring up a somewhat weird topic?
お、いいよ。もうふけってまいりましたので、
Oh, sure. Moving on to the next one,
はい、お風呂で異性に会わせてもいい場所の限界を教えてください、という
"Please tell us the limit of where it's okay to let the opposite sex see you in the bath!"
謎の！
What a mysterious...
なにそれ！ えー！
What is that?! Eh?!
限界！ 限界！ 誰この異性って！
Limit? Limit? Who is this "opposite sex"?!
何なの？ そうなの？ なんか、え、店？
What's that? Is that right? Like, um, a store?
彼女？どっち？
Girlfriend? Which one?
この、だ、誰なの？異性もだ、誰なの？わかんないけど。
Who, who is this? Even if it's the opposite sex, who is it? I don't know, but...
わかんないけど。
I don't know, but...
でもお風呂は、彼女なのだとしたら、彼女が洗いたいならどこまででもいいんじゃない？って思った。
But if we assume it's a girlfriend, if she wants to wash you, wouldn't anywhere be fine? I thought.
なんか、結果、どう、どういうこと？その、その、コウヨが彼女だったら、ラミはどこも洗ってもいいってこと？
Like, wait, what does that mean? If Koyori is the girlfriend, does that mean Lamy can wash anywhere?
あ、違う違う違う、え、何？ラミたんが洗ってくれるの？
Ah, no no no, wait, what? Lamy-tan will wash you?
待て、話が変わってくるんだけど、そうだったらっていうこと。
Wait, the topic is shifting, but if that were the case...
え、なんか、え、どっちだろ？えっと、コウヨが彼女で、で、えっと、彼女が、え、君の全部洗ってあげたいの！って言ってきて、自分もまんざらではないなら、全部洗わせていいんじゃない？
Um, which is it? Let's see, if Koyori is the girlfriend, and she says, "I want to wash all of you!", and you wouldn't mind it, isn't it fine to let her wash everything?
おお、あ、この、あのマシュマロの人になりきっての今、なりきった上で、抜けた上で、そう言うこと？
Oh, ah, this, you're roleplaying as the marshmallow person right now, right? After getting into character, that's what you mean.
え、たぶん、でもこのマシュマロの人は、団体長たちがその、異性が洗うならどこまで許せるかっていうわりだと
Um, but I assumed this marshmallow person was asking how far group leaders would allow the opposite sex to wash them—
洗ってほしいなっていう側、言われる側？洗ってほしいなって
The side wanting to be washed, or the side being told "I want to wash you"?
洗ってほしいなって言われる側？ え、この子が、えっと、彼女に対して洗ってほしいなって言いたいのかもしれないかな。
The side being told "I want to wash you"? Wait, this child might want to say to her, "I want you to wash me."
そしたら、どこまで求めていいですか？っていうことにするじゃあ。
So then, "How far can I ask?" Let's make it about that, then.
どういうこと、どういうこと？ なんか、その、自分の立場が分からない。自分、自分は誰？
What does that mean, what does that mean? Like, I don't know my own standpoint. Who am I?
この子の、この子の彼女だとして、このおマシュマロ主の、このおマシュマロ主の彼女だとして、で、このおマシュマロ主であるこのカレピー君が、
As this kid's girlfriend, as this marshmallow sender's girlfriend, and this marshmallow sender, "Karepi-kun",
一緒にお風呂に入ろうということになりました。
decided to take a bath together.
で、このカレピー君は、あの、洗ってほしそうっぽい自分の体をを。
And this Karepi-kun seems like he wants his body washed.
あ、そうそうそう。洗ってほしいっぽい感じかね。ねえ、ちょっとお風呂行こうよみたいなときに、あの、どこまでだったらラミに超えれないのか。
Ah, exactly. He seems to want to be washed. Like when he says, "Hey, let's take a bath together," how far can he go without crossing the line with Lamy?
すごいな、もうライン超えてると思うけど私。
That's amazing, I think he's already crossed the line though.
超えてるか。もうお風呂入ってんんならもう
Crossed it? Well, if you're already in the bath, then—
もう完結してない？ ないそんな。
Isn't that already complete? No way.
え、でもなんか普通だったら背中までよなって思ったんだよね。
But you know, normally I'd think up to your back, right?
ああ、なるほどね。背中を流す。背中の洗いこまでなの。
Ah, I see. Washing the back. Up to washing the back.
いやも、で もラミが交友の体を洗ってもいいんだとしたらどこまででも洗います。
But if Lamy is allowed to wash Koyori's body, she'll wash anywhere.
嘘！ えらい！ どこはでもね。
No way! Wow! Anywhere, really.
いやもう脱いだも脱いだもどこまででも洗うよ。
Lamy will wash anywhere she takes off!
ほんとに？ 洗うけど。
Really? She'll wash, but...
え、僕が男だったらどこまででも洗ってくれるならじゃあ。
Uh, if I were a guy, if you'd wash anywhere, then...
お願いします。
Please.
え、でもさ、ラミ、団長の体洗ってくれるって、言うけど、え、団長、あれだよ、ちょっとややこしいよ、体洗うルーティンが。
But wait, Lamy, you say you'll wash the Dancho's body, but Dancho, you know, your body-washing routine is a bit complicated.
ラミも、ラミも、たぶん美容に色々やってるからちょっと細かいかもしれないけど。
Lamy does a lot of beauty stuff too, so it might be a bit meticulous.
あ、いい、覚える覚える。まずは、その、体を洗うじゃん。
Ah, right, remember, remember. First, you wash the body, right?
体は洗うけど、あの、大事あるじゃんね、その下の大事なところは、うちの石鹸で洗ってほしい。
She'll wash the body, but for the important parts underneath, she wants them washed with our soap.
いや、さすがにさ、そこまでさ。
Come on, really, up to there...
ラミィも別の石鹸で洗ってさ
Lamy washes with a different soap too...
そういうのちゃんとやってくれるならいいけど
If you're going to do that properly, that's fine, but...
あ、ラミィね
Ah, Lamy, right.
分かったこと全部覚えるわ 1から全部全部覚えるから
I'll memorize everything. I'll remember every single thing from scratch,
当てはめてもらっていい？ それならいいかな
so can you match it to me? If so, that might be fine.
うん、お任せしろ
Yeah, leave it to me.
またラミィちゃん この番組やるとラミィちゃんが良い女であることがどんどんさ 世間にバレていくだけの
Also, every time Lamy-chan does this show, more and more people in the world realize what a great woman Lamy-chan is—
いやありがたい
Haha, thank you!
時間 え、でもさ、こういうのも言ってね、あの何がどうとかね、全部覚えるんで
Time— Uh, but you know, say things like that too, like what's how and all, since I can remember everything.
これだからあんまり特にないから、ラミィちゃんがやってるやつをやってもらった方がきれいに
Since there isn't really anything special about this, it might be cleaner if you just do what Lamy-chan does—
うん、なるほどなるほど
Ah, I see, I see.
お任せあれ
Leave it to me!
でも、今の分かったのは、女の子の体洗いたいんだったら、女の子結構ね、そのいろいろ気にしてることあるかな
But what I understood just now is, if you want to wash a girl's body, girls care a lot about various things, right?
そこをちゃんと気づってあげるといいんじゃないかっていう感じですかね？そうね
If you can be considerate of that, that's probably good, right? Right, yeah.
それができたら120点だね。120点ですね。ちょっと面白かったんで
If you can do that, that's 120 points. Exactly 120 points. I thought it was funny, so I just said it, sorry.
え、じゃあちょっとノエたんだからこその、恋愛相談モードに入りたいと思います。はい、恋愛相談の
Um, then I'd like to enter the romance consultation mode, specifically because it's Noel-tan. Yes, for the first romance consultation...
ご紹介としましょう。 ええ、団長がいるということなので、ご相談させてください。
Let's introduce it. Since the Danchou is here, please let us consult with you.
はい、今自分にはおっぱいの大きい彼女がいます。おー
Right now, I have a girlfriend with big breasts. Ohh!
はい、そして何を隠そう自分は第の巨乳星人であります。おー
Yes, and needless to say, I am a huge fan of big breasts. Oh!
ですが、ウィンウィンなんですけど、彼女にはカッコいいところだけを見せたく、そのことについては一切言わず、別に興味ねえしみたいな態度を取ってしまいます。
But win-win as it is, I want to show only my cool side to my girlfriend, so I never mention that, and instead act like I'm not interested at all.
あ、なんかちょっとさっきのキャンディにちょっと繋がる感じだけど
Ah, it kind of connects to that candy thing from earlier, but...
このまま我慢してカッコいい自分を見せ続けるか、それとも惹かれることを前提にありのままの自分をさらけ出すのがいいか、どっちがいいんでしょうか？おっぱいぷるんぷるんだそうです。
Should I endure this and keep showing my cool self, or should I reveal my true self assuming she's attracted to me—which is better? Her breasts are bouncy, apparently.
コロナでもノエたん決まってるでしょ答え。いや決まって
Even in COVID, Noel-tan, you have your answer locked in, right? Well, it's locked in, but...
まあ、何ヶ月かとかね、そういうのも関係すると思うけどでもさ
Well, how many months it's been and stuff probably matters too, but still...
やっぱさらけ出した方がいい
After all, it's better to bare it all!
だって、いつまでもね、そのさ、かっこいい姿
Because, you know, forever showing that cool appearance...
いや、最初だけだよ本当に。バレる。てか、なんならバレてると思う、もう。
No, that's only at first, really. She'll find out. Or rather, she probably already knows.
おっぱい星人だってことが。目線でバレるんじゃないかってコメントが
That you're a breast fanatic. There's a comment saying she might figure it out from your gaze.
ああ、どうですか？
Ah, what do you think?
なんか、見つめ返すことある？いや、なんか団長感じない、その感じたそう、街中とか
Do you ever gaze back? Well, like, don't you feel it, Danchou—like feeling that in town or somewhere?
え、なんか、あるよね、そのさ、結構コメントとかでもさ、
Eh, like, there is that, right? Like, even in the comments,
え、となりの大胸筋がでかいと、目線とか気にならないですか？ラミィちゃん。その、おっぱい
Eh, 'When the person next to you has huge pectoral muscles, don't you mind their gaze?' Lamy-chan. Like, about breasts—
あ、気になったことない。
Ah, I've never been concerned about that.
え、ないの！？大体コンビニの店員さんとか見ちゃうそう。ない？
Eh, none!? Usually convenience store clerks and stuff might look. None?
いや、ラミィでかすら毎回あったら見てるよ。
No, even Lamy looks every single time if it's there.
ま、それはそう、見ちゃうな。うん、うん。
Well, that's true, you'd look. Yeah, yeah.
それ感じてないんか？
So you don't sense it?
なんか、あんまりもしかしたら、その、そういう感じないような子だったなら、気づいてないかもしれないけど
Maybe she's just not the type to feel that way, so she hasn't noticed,
えでもさ、ほら、ラミィとかね、あのこよりちゃんもあるからさ、え感じたりする？街中で
but you know, Lamy and Koyori-chan have them too, so do you feel it? Out in town—
ちょっと、街中は、街中は、ない。
Umm, out in town, out in town, no.
手はないけど、でも、あ、今なんかちょっと目線したなって思うことは、あるかな。あの、面と向かってね話すタイミングとかがあるとか、お店の人とかもね。
Not really, but, well, there are times when I think, 'Ah, they just gave me a glance right now.' Like when there's a timing to talk face-to-face, or with shop staff too.
いやあ、えでも、ど、どうだろう。なんかこよ的には、うん、うん。
Yeah. But how is it? Like, for Koyo, yeah, yeah.
でも、ちょっとおっぱい星人まで、うん、をお、急に言って、なんか、それですごい何かが起きてしまったらちょっと怖いなって、この子の気持ちになると、
But if you suddenly bring up 'breast fanatic' and something terrible happens because of that, it's a bit scary, if you put yourself in this kid's shoes.
そうだね、なんか、いきなりはね、
That's right, like, suddenly—
いきなりだと、え、もしかして、大胸筋、おっぱいが大きいから近づけたのかなとか、そんなふうに思われちゃうかもだから、
Suddenly doing it might make her think, 'Eh, did he get close to me because my pecs / breasts are big?' She might think that, so...
怖いかも。
It could be scary.
確かにそれは。本当に、付き合ってどれぐらいの期間なのかプラス、
True. Truly, plus how long they've been dating,
あとはもうちょっと、徐々にだね、やっぱ徐々に、うん、ていう、なんか
and also a bit more gradually, after all, gradually, yeah—like, praising them,
褒める感じで、が、難しいよな。
in a praising way... it's difficult.
いや、確かにな。難しい。これは、なんか一気に難しくなくなってきた、確かに。
Yeah, true. Difficult. This suddenly became not so difficult—true.
でも、かっこつけるのは、なんか、あれかな、続かないと思うんだよね。
But acting cool, I wonder if that's something that won't last.
そうだね。別に興味ねえしは、嘘になっちゃうというかさ、そう、嘘嘘、そう、嘘になっちゃう。
Right. Saying 'I'm not interested at all' would turn into a lie, right? Yeah, lies, lies, right, it becomes a lie.
もしそういう、その言えるようなタイミングが来たときには、うん、あの
If a timing comes where you can say something like that, um, like...
君自身が好きなことは大前提に、おっぱいも大好きだよみたいな。
With the premise that you like her as a person yourself, something like 'I love your breasts too!'
言う、言うことないと思うけど、ないかな。まあでも、なんかあれなんです、別に好き
You probably wouldn't say that, but maybe not. Well, but, you know, it's not that I like...
なしっていう態度は
An attitude of \"that's a no\"...
なしで普通の巨乳星人はいいのかもね、なんかその
maybe just being an average big-boobed alien is fine, you know...
わざわざね、おっぱい星人です宣言することはなくていいから
You don't need to go out of your way to declare \"I'm a boob alien!\"
なんか、そうね、なんかちょっと強がってるというか、クールぶってるというか
Like, right, it's a bit like acting tough, or playing it cool.
でも団長だったら嬉しいけどね、ちなみに。
Though if it were Danchou, I'd be happy, by the way.
なんか、おっぱい星人だったら、おっぱい星人？
Like, if you're a boob alien, a boob alien?
確かに。おっぱい星人めいてる感じして、うん、嬉しい。
True. It feels like a boob alien, yeah, I'm happy.
嬉しい。
I'm happy.
ラミィちゃんは、嬉しい？ラミィちゃんもね、立派な…
Lamy-chan, are you happy? Lamy-chan also has a splendid...
おっぱい星人イン？
Boob alien in?
おっぱい星人、嬉しいよ。もうおっぱい星人だったら全然、「お、ラミィの胸に飛んでおいで」ってなるけど。
Boob alien? I'd be happy. If you're a boob alien, I'd be like, \"Oh, come fly to Lamy's chest.\"
この胸の音でこう、繋ぎ止められるみたいなところもある、なんか。
There's also a part where you can be held together by this chest, somehow.
え、そこ？そんなのはないけど。
Eh, there? There's no such thing.
え、ないか、ないか。
Eh, no, right, no.
え、おっぱい、その今好き合っててことじゃん？好き合ってる上で、おっぱいまで好きなら、もう、うん、あ、もうだって、もう魅力かける2やんみたいな、
Eh, boob, you mean you currently like each other right? If you like each other up to the boobs, then already, like, it's like charm times 2,
じゃあずっとこのまま好きでいて続けてくれるなみたいな安心感。
so you'll keep on liking me forever like that kind of sense of security.
いや、なんかさ、男のが、なんかその自分自身にとっての、おっぱいはそんなに価値はあんま感じてなくて…
No, like, for men, for themselves, they don't feel that much value in boobs...
自分の、うん。
Their own, yeah.
え、それ、それ、もったいない！
Eh, that, that's such a waste!
もったいないよ。
That's a waste.
うん。でも、世の中には、そういうね、好きな人がいるっていうのは分かってるのよ。やっぱりね、世間一般的に。
Yeah. But in the world, you know, I know there are people who like that. After all, generally speaking.
だから、ありがたいなみたいには思うけど、それで、なんかそういう繋ぎ止められるとか、強みだみたいな自信には、なかなかあなんないなぁ。
So, I think it's appreciated, but it doesn't really translate into confidence like \"I can hold them together\" or \"It's my strength\".
なるほどね。
I see.
そう、ちょっと余裕がない女なのかもしれない。
Yeah, maybe she's a woman with no leeway.
その、自分の価値を見出したいみたいな、たぶん自分自身がないからなのかな？
Like wanting to find her own worth, probably because she lacks self-confidence?
ああ、そう、そういうところもでも、なんかかわいいけどね。かわいいよ、失言て言われてるのです。
Ah, yeah, but even those parts are kind of cute though. It's cute, she's being told it's a slip of the tongue.
繋ぎ止められるは失言だったみたいですね。
Being held together seems to have been a slip of the tongue.
はい、では続いて、えー、これちょっと、え、答えてあげたいなという。
Okay, then moving on, um, I'd like to answer this one.
はい、ののすののお二人、そしてゲストの団長こんばんは！
Hello to Nonosuno-no-o-futari and guest Danchou!
私は現在、海外で生活しています。現地の方から好意を寄せてくれていますが、私自身は数年後には日本へ帰らなければなりません。
I currently live overseas. Someone locally has feelings for me, but I myself must return to Japan in a few years.
そのため、悲しい思いをさせるよりも、現地でもっと素敵な方と過ごしてもらうほうがいいのではと思ってしまいます。
Therefore, rather than making them sad, I find myself thinking it's better for them to spend time with someone more wonderful locally.
3人の意見をお聞きしたいですというちょっと真面目モードですね。
I want to hear the three of you's opinions—a rather serious mode.
ああ、すごい。うわあ。これ難しいね。
Ah, wow. Whoa. This is difficult.
難しいね。気持ちはわかるね。
It is difficult. I understand the feeling.
そっか。でもなんか、正直に言ってあげてもいいのかなって思っている。
I see. But I feel like it's okay to be honest with them.
ああ、数年後には帰らなきゃいけないよって。
Ah, that I have to go back in a few years.
そう。から、その、やっぱり難しいと思うけど、
Right. So, though I think it's difficult after all,
え、もうなんか、そんで、でも愛してくれるなら、日本に来るかみたいな。
Um, like, and if they still love you, come to Japan or something?
え、まあ、難しいよね。どこ、どこのあれなのかも分からないけど、ね、遠距離になっちゃうしね。難しいよね。
Well, it's difficult, right? I don't know where it is, but, you know, it becomes long distance too. It's difficult.
付いてこいよって家ってコメントもありますけど、どうでしょうか。
There are comments like \"Just come with me!\", what do you think?
あ、そう、積極的なさ、人。
Ah, right, active people.
やっぱ寄せてくれてる人、まあ本当に、かよちゃんとかも、やっぱ数年後には帰らなきゃいけないんだよね。
People who show affection, well really, like Kayo-chan too, after all, you have to go back in a few years, right?
っていう話ををした上で、なんか悲しい思いさせるよりもとかはさ、相手側のさ、やっぱさ、気持ちだから、自分のそうゆ状況を伝えた上でどうするかは、相手に委ねてもいいんじゃないかなって思ったりするかな。
After talking about that, rather than making them sad, it's the other person's feelings after all, so after communicating your situation, maybe you can leave it up to them to decide what to do.
どう、あ、どうい、なんかさ、
How, ah, how, like,
恋愛とかそういうのってさ、ファンタジーだと思ってて、そう。だからなんか、こう理屈じゃないんじゃないかとというなんか夢も持ってて、団長の中で。
Romance and things like that, you know, I think they're fantasy, right. So, like, maybe it's not just about logic, I have that kind of dream inside Danchou.
だからお互いのそういう気持ちで、なんかこう無理難題を乗り越えていくこともあるかもなんで。
So with each other's feelings like that, maybe there are times when you overcome difficult challenges.
ちょっと気持ちを素直に行くのもいいじゃな、なんか大人になりすぎなくてさ。
It might be good to follow your feelings honestly, without being too grown-up.
ああ、する。
Ah, true.
すごい。いい言葉や。大人になりすぎない。ね。
Amazing. Good words. Not being too grown-up. Right.
どうだろうなーって感じです。団長は。
That's how it is. Danchou's
同じ。
Same.
いいと思います。いいと思います。なので、ちょっと向き合ってみてください。
I think it's good. I think it's good. So, please face it.
お、はい。さちはれということで、続いていきましょう。
Oh, yes. Wishing you happiness, let's continue.
え、こちらはですね、えー、女子ホロリスです。
Um, this one is, um, a female hololive listener.
恋愛相談なんですけど、
It's a romance advice question, but
この前他大学の男性と3回目のデートに行ってきました。
the other day I went on a third date with a guy from another university.
3回目なので告白とか何か仕掛けてくるかなと思ったんですけど、
Since it's the third time, I thought he might confess or make a move,
何もありませんでした。
nothing happened at all.
それから私の気持ちも冷めてきてしまって、LINEとかする気になれなくて、このままでいいのかな悩んでます。
And my feelings have cooled down, I don't feel like texting on LINE, and I'm wondering if this is okay.
私はどうすればいいでしょうか? 助けてーー
What should I do? Help me~~
ああかわいい。
Ah, cute.
3回目のデート、3回目どうなんですかね?
The third date... what about the third date?
どうなんだろうな。
I wonder how it is.
3回目のデート、何もありませんでした。
The third date... nothing happened.
え、これ、え？ デートということは
Eh? This... eh? Since it's a date,
え、これは付き合ってってこと？ なくない？ ない、ない、ない。
eh, does this mean they're going out? No way. No, no, no.
ないけど、3回デートして、3回一緒にでかけたら、
No, but if you go on 3 dates and go out 3 times together,
もうなんか告白とかそういう感じになるのかなみたいな。
it feels like it's going to turn into a confession or something like that.
なるほど、なんか冷めちゃったなら、もうそれが答えって
I see. If you've already cooled down, then that's the answer,
男の人がうっちぎすぎて本当は女の子のこと好きなんだけど、なんか告白する勇気がなくてっていう
the guy is too timid and actually likes the girl, but doesn't have the courage to confess,
パターンもあると、じゃそっちのパターンかなって思えるけど、コメントが結構やっぱキープとかも言うのよ。
there's also that pattern, so you might think it's that pattern, but comments often mention things like keeping someone on the hook.
難しいね。難しいけど、
It's difficult. It's difficult, but
冷めちゃったなら、なんかな、3回目なので告白とかしてしてくれるかなっていう、
if you've cooled down, like, 'since it's the third time, will he confess or something?',
けっこう厳しいこと言うんですけど、ていうなんか期待をしてるのがちょっと、
I'm going to say something pretty harsh, but having that expectation is...
なんかあの、今後のためにもそう、そういう価値観じゃないほうがいいかもなって思った感じがある。
I feel like, for the sake of the future, maybe it's better not to have those kinds of values.
と言うと、なんかその3回目のデートでは告白するっていう決まりは全くなかったりとか、結構この世の中、なんか告白せずナアナアで付き合ったことになったみたいな人たちもいたりもするから、
That is to say, there's no fixed rule that you have to confess on the third date, and in this world, there are people who started dating casually without a confession,
その、なんだろう、絶対に起こるイベントではないので、
so, you know, it's not an event that is guaranteed to happen,
なんかその期待してなかったら冷めなかったのかなとか、そういうの考えてみたほうがいいのかなと思った。
so I thought maybe if you hadn't expected it, you wouldn't have cooled down, and it might be good to think about things like that.
確かに、なんか、あれやね、
True, like, you know,
多分、その相手が何かなってくれるみたいな、男の子がその、あのプロポーズしてくれたりとかさ、その付き合っていったりとかさ、
probably, waiting for the other person to do something, like the boy proposing or asking you out,
では受け身になってはいるよね、この3回目ってさ。
you're being passive on this third date, right?
まあそうだね。まあ女の子はね、その願望は確かにあるよね、あるよね。
Well, that's true. Well, girls definitely have that desire, right?
だけど、やっぱ、人によっては、なかなか積極的な男の子じゃない子もいるし、
However, depending on the person, there are guys who aren't very proactive,
でも、やっぱそう付き合うってなると、もうそこらへん、うん、もう好きになったら、やっぱ自分からね動くのも、
and when it comes to dating, if you come to like them, I think it's important to make a move yourself too,
大事だ と思うから、そうどうすればいいか、助けてということなので、
so I think it's important, and since she's asking 'what should I do, help me,'
本当に、もうきっかりこの男の子とはいいかなってなったら連絡取らなくてもいいし、
truly, if you think 'I'm done with this guy,' you don't even have to contact him anymore,
でもまだ、で もほんとちょっと好きな気持ちがあるんだってなら、やっぱ行ってみるのもいいと思うんだよね。
but if you still have a little bit of feelings for him, I think it's good to try going out with him.
サメ、なんかここで冷めちゃうのはちょっともったいないなあって思う。
It's a bit of a waste to cool down right here, I feel.
そうね、3回目の日までデートに行ったんだもんね、事実。
That's right, you actually went on dates up to the third time.
時間を割いてね、お互いね、お互いの時間を使って会ってたわけなのだから、
You spent time, both of you used your time to meet, so
多分向こうにも好意があることはあるんだろうね、だって3回目もデート行ったんだもんね。
the other person probably has feelings for you too, since they went on a third date.
でもやっぱちょっと期待しちゃったんだね、多分ね、そうよね。
But you expected a bit too much, didn't you? Probably, yeah.
だから、なんかその、本当に気になってるなら、自分からどんどんいっちゃってもいいんじゃないかな、やっぱまあ。
So, if you're really interested, maybe you should just go for it yourself, after all.
そうですね、なんか、一旦、その期待してた自分を無くして、
That's true, like, once you let go of your expectations,
で、その告白してくれなかったっていうのも全部無くして、
and let go of the fact that he didn't confess,
その子が好きなのかどうかっていうことを考えてみて、
and just think about whether you really like that person or not,
それで好きなら、4回目行ってみようぜ。
and if you like him, let's try a fourth date!
誘ってみてもいいんじゃない?
Why don't you try inviting him?
って言う感じですけど
...That's how it is, but...
人に期待していいことは一つもないので、これ恋愛
I have nothing to expect from anyone, so... romance...
恋愛、でも恋愛じゃなくても
Well, romance, whether it's romance or not...
そうね。うーん。なんかやっぱり
Yeah. Well, expectation...
なんていうの、期待ってエゴなんでって思うと
is ego, so if you think that,
ちょっと楽になるのかな生き方が。
maybe living becomes a bit easier.
なるほどね。
That's true.
うんうん。はい。それでは続いて、えっと男の子ですね。
Then, moving on to... uh, boy.
はい。
Okay.
と、グイグイ話しかけてくるのはどんな意図や背景を持っているのかという、え、悩み相談でございます。
What kind of intent and background is behind someone coming to flirt persistently? That's the consultation.
お。
Oh.
と、同じ案件作業をしてるが直接会話が少ない後輩女性、え、職場飲み会開催場所移動前に後輩女性から「今日の飲み会席ですよね？
And, working on the same project, but with a junior female colleague who rarely talks directly: "Since it's the workplace party today before moving locations,
よく食べるとお聞きしたので、生ませても大丈夫ですよね？」
I heard you eat a lot, so I'm fine if you let me eat, right?"
みたいな、普通の会話が来る。
Like that, kind of normal conversation.
偶然にも座席のま、座席が同じ場所。
And coincidentally, the seats are right next to each other.
自分はコミュニケーションは高めと自負しているが、不意に迫られると押し込まれるタイプ。
I pride myself on high communication skills, but I'm the type to get flustered when suddenly cornered.
「何かあるのでは」と背景をみつつさりげない会話で終了。
Ending with a subtle conversation hinting "Is there something?"
そのごときに進展なし、今のご時世何があるか分からないというてってまえをおくチキン野郎です。年齢は30代前半ですという。
Progressing not at all, with no idea what's going on now—a timid bastard, age early 30s.
あー。
Ah.
ま、こういう行動をとる女の子は、もし自分のことの后輩女子だとしたら、うん、どうなのかなみたいな妄想ですね。
Well, a girl who takes this action... If I knew she was my junior female colleague, I'd wonder what she's thinking, right? That kind of delusion.
あー。
Ah.
もうさ、これなんか、相手が好意を持ってるとかそういうんじゃなくて、なんでこうゆう
Or rather, this is... Not that the other person holds affection, but why do they...
どういう意図や背景を持っているんだろうかと。
what kind of intent or background do they have?
まあ、要するに、おそらく、あの、この行動してくるって自分のこと好きなの？
Well, basically, probably... this kind of action coming means "Do you like me?"
っていうのを、その女子ってどうなの？って聞きたいんだと思う。
They want to ask "What is a girl feeling?"
あー。
Ah.
あー、なるほど。
Ah, I see.
でも、あれだよね、実際にその、なんだろう、向こうからのアクションとしては、あの、今日飲み会来ますよね？いっぱい飲めますよね？って言われたこと、うん、だけだよね？
But, you know, actually... like, from the other side's action, "You're coming to the drinking party today, right? You'll drink a lot, right?"—being told that...
うん、確かに今書いてある内容だとなんかそれだけかも。
Well, true, if it's just the content written now, maybe that's all.
うん。
Yeah.
そう、同じ座席とかはあったけど
Right, they sat in the same seat, but...
うんうんうんうん。
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
うーん、なんに、なにもなくても聞くかな？みたいな内容って感じ？
So like, will they listen even if there's nothing? That kind of content, you know?
まあ、うーん。
Well, um...
なんか、こう、ま、そうよ、飲み会に行くっていうさ、きっかけっていうか、あるから、とりあえず、ま、飲み会までちょっと、テンションを、ま、飲み会ってさ、テンション上がるものか分からないけどさ、
Like, they have a reason to go to the drinking party, so first, until the drinking party, their tension...
飲み会でテンション上がって、で、なんか
drinking party tension goes up, and then they kind of...
ま、話しかけたぐらいな感じなのかな。
talked to them a bit—is that the kind of feeling?
うんうんうんうん。
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
ていう感じだよね、なんか本当に。
That's the kind of feeling, really.
まあ、そうだな、でも内容としてはグイグイと話しかけに来るっていうことも別であったのかどうなのか、まあ確かに数すうの悩みはあるかもね。
Well, that's true, but as for the content, coming to talk persistently might be a separate matter, or maybe not... well, true, there might be quite a lot of it.
うん。
Yeah.
うーん、なんかコメランは、なんか「何もないぞ、安心しろ」で一致しているみたいなんですけども、
Umm, like, as for Komeran, it's like, "There's nothing, so rest assured," they seem to be in agreement, but...
（笑）
laughs
え、でもなんかもし、すごい、え、そんなに私にだけ話しかけに来るみたいな、みんなにさ、同じように、そうそうそう、なんか飲み会の人数を増やしたくてみんなに言ってる可能性もあるかな？
Eh, but like, what if it's super... eh, if they come to talk *only* to me, like everyone, like, they want to increase the number of people for the drinking party and might be telling everyone...
その
That...
でも、自分にばっかりいろんなこと聞いてくるなってもし思うのであれば、あの、なんか聞いてもいいかなって思っちゃった。
Even so, if they think "They're asking me about all sorts of things only," if they think that,
そんなに、なんか、俺のこと気にしてくれてんの？みたいな。
Like, "What are you even caring about me for?"
ちょっと軽く、そんなグイグイ来てるならこっちも軽く
Mildly, if they're coming that persistently, we should mildly...
いや、じゃあ、デジャブ？デジャブ？
Yeah. Déjà vu? Déjà vu?
デジャブ。
Déjà vu.
いや、さっき、さっきこれ、さっき私言ったけど、そう、なんだよね、難しいんだよね、その
Yeah, recently... recently, I've been saying this over and over, but it's hard, right? That...
この方も心配してるしね、ちょっと。
This person is also worried, right, a bit?
確かにね。
True.
そうなんだよね、すごい慎重派な方なんで。
That's right, they're a very cautious type, so...
だから、もう、本当に、うん、なんだろう。
So like, really... um, what should I say?
え、グイグイ系だったら、え、なんか、やっぱ、さっきね、けっこう
If it's a persistent type, well, like, recently, quite...
こより、だめそうだな、こんくらい半数。
Koyori is like, "Koyori can't do it either," about half.
こよりちゃん男の子でこういう悩める小羊だったらちょっとやばかったかも。
If Koyori is a boy and can get this troubled as a sheep, it might be dangerous.
やばかったかも、よかった。女でよかったな、ぎりぎり。
It might be dangerous, or rather, if it's a girl, it was barely okay, just barely.
だから、まあ、うん、そう、なんかグイグイ、その、まだね、情報も薄いしってことは、そんなに他でグイグイエピソードが揃ってないってことだから
So like, persistently, well, still, you know, information is thin, which means there aren't many other episodes of being persistent, so...
いったん、まあ、普通に、うん、なんかや、なんだろう、仕事続けて、で、そんな会話やってで、いい気がするな。
First, well, normally, um, like, continue working normally, have a conversation like that, and I have a feeling...
そうですね。
Right.
うん。
Yeah.
そう、だね。多分そんな、あの、意
That's right. Probably not so much, um, intent...
して、多分、結構いろんな人に話しかけるタイプの女性だったんじゃなかろうか
And maybe she's the type of woman who talks to all sorts of people...
という、性格な感じかも…
That sort of personality vibe...
あれね、二人でごはん行きましょうとか言われたらもう一回考えてみたな。
Like, if she said "Let's go get food together, two of us," I'd think about it again.
あ、そうかね。感じかもね。
Ah, is that so? Maybe so.
はい。ということで。
Right. With that being said...
はい、はい。
Yes, yes.
じゃあ、あと2つ読んでもいいですか？
Now, can I read two more?
もちろん！
Of course!
女の子と男の子それぞれ行こうと思うんですけれど、
We're going to talk about girls and boys separately, but...
可愛いやつです。え、学生の女子団長です！
It's a cute one. Ah, a female student Dancho!
今、第3、今絶賛片思い中なのだすが、
She's currently—third—currently unrequitedly in love, but...
どうすれば相手に振り向いてもらえますか？モテる行動とかヘアスタイル教えて欲しいです！
how can I get them to turn their attention to me? I want you to teach me attractive behaviors and hairstyles!
ちなみにユニバのアトラクション二人で乗ったことあります。幸せ！
By the way, we've ridden an attraction together at Universal Studios. Bliss!
可愛い！
So cute!
優勝！
Absolute win!
クソ可愛いんですけど。
She's freaking adorable.
可愛いね。
So cute.
どうですか。モテる行動とかヘアスタイル教えて欲しいって。
What do you think? Asking for attractive behaviors and hairstyles.
え、でもさ、その好きな男の子がさ、どんなスタイルが好きなのかにもよるくない？
Well, but, doesn't it depend on what style the boy she likes prefers?
そうなんだよね。
That's true.
確かにね。
Definitely.
これはね、あの、その、この子に似合うとかも大事だったりするしな。
Also, things like whether it suits her are important too.
まあでも、本当に一つだけ言えるのはすでに可愛い。もう、可愛いよ可愛いよ。
Well, but really, one thing I can say is she's already cute. She's just so cute.
もういっぱい、いっぱい笑ってね、そう笑う女の子がもう最高やから。
Just smile a lot, a smiling girl is simply the best.
確かに。愛情だよ愛情。愛情、本当。
True. It's affection. Affection, really.
男は度胸、女は愛情。
Courage for men, affection for women.
昔から言うよね。
People have been saying that forever.
いや、でも大事だと思うよ。笑顔よく。俺の前だとすごい一等一番この子笑ってくれるな、とかさ。
No, but I think it's important. Smiling a lot. Like, "She smiles the most when she's in front of me," and stuff.
絶対キュンとくるポイントでしょ。
That's definitely a heart-fluttering point.
そうだね。本当。なんかこのさ、うん、なんか幸せ
That's true. Really. Like, you know...
可愛いなっていうの、思ってるやつを
Thinking "she's so cute," and keeping that in mind...
なんか伝わるぐらいニコニコしきり話しかけたりとかしてもいいのかなって。
I wonder if it's okay to smile enough to convey it and talk to them often.
そう、だね。
That's right.
おもっちゃいます。
I tend to think that.
大事、大事。いや、本当。
Important, very important. Truly.
もう自信持ってすでに可愛いので、
Be confident because you're already cute,
あとあれか、なんかすう、あのもしヘアスタイルとか変えたいなら
And also, like, if you want to change your hairstyle,
なんかさ、なんか、その好きな男の子の髪型とかあるの？って聞いて、
you could ask, "Do you have a preferred hairstyle for girls?"
次の日それをやってくるすずみやはるみですよ。
And then show up the next day rocking that style, like Suzumiya Haruhi.
あ、もうめっちゃ意識してるじゃん！
Ah, that's so obvious you're into them!
俺のこと。え、そういうのどう、どう思う？
About me. Eh, what do you think about that?
え、可愛くない？
Right? Isn't that cute?
よね？可愛いよね。
Right? So cute.
そういうのやってみちゃってもね、いいかもしれない、なって
Doing something like that might be nice, I think.
思います。
That's what I think.
それをやってなんか変な感じになったらどうしようって今ちょっとソワソワしてるんですけど
Though I'm feeling a bit restless wondering what if it turns out weird...
責任負えないな。
I can't take responsibility for that!
でも、まあ、相手の男の子がどういう感じなのか分からないからね。
Well, but we don't know what kind of guy he is, after all.
ねえ、でも可愛いでしょう。
Right, but she's cute, isn't she?
うん、可愛いよね。してほしいです。
Yeah, very cute. I'd love for her to do it.
それでは、え、ラストは男子からのいこうかなと思うんだけれど、ちょっとすぐにしようか。
Now then, for the last one, I think we'll go with one from a boy...
本当に、もうホクホクしてる。
Seriously, I'm already all warmed up inside.
ホクホクで本当ね、恋愛楽しいよね。人の恋愛をこう感じるだけでも。
It's so heartwarming. Romance is fun, even just experiencing it through others.
こちらですね、やっぱりちょっとノエル先輩ということで、ちょうど、あのノエたんということでね、ちょっと
And for this one, since it's Noel-senpai, right—Noe-tan—
「大人の女性ならではの魅力をお持ちの、すずのぬえだんさんに質問です！私はいつか、素敵ななお姉さんタイプの女性とお付き合いをして、お互いに支え合えるような関係を築きたいと思っています。」
"This is a question for Shirogane Noel, who has the charm unique to an adult woman! I hope to someday date a wonderful older-sister type woman and build a supportive relationship."
「そこでお聞きしたいのですが、お姉さんタイプの女性と付き合うための秘訣や、こういう男性だといいなと思うポイントなどはありますでしょうか？」
"I'd like to ask: are there any secrets to dating an older-sister type woman, or points that make you think 'this kind of guy is great'?"
「ぜひお二人の意見、3人ですねの意見やアドバイスをいただけますと嬉しいです！」
"I would be happy to hear the opinions and advice of the two of you—well, three of you!"
あらあら、あらあら。大人の女性、あらあら。
My, my, my, my. An adult woman, my, my.
あらあら、あらあら。大人の女性に憧れている。ほろりさん。あらあら、あらあら。
My, my. Aspiring to be an adult woman. Horori-san. My, my, my, my.
「お姉さんタイプの女性とお付き合いするための秘訣…」これどうなんだろうね。
"Secrets to dating an older-sister type woman..." I wonder what that is.
え、でも…
Well, but...
そうだな なんか別に 変にさ 背伸びしなくていいと思って…イイ感出してるね？
That's true. Like, you don't need to try too hard to act mature... giving off a good vibe?
そうね！
That's right! [Laughs]
そうだな なんか本当に こう真面目に そう 生きて なんか背一杯 背一杯で頑張ってる…
That's true. Like, really living earnestly, and doing your absolute best...
ところとかを…
and those parts, you know...
なんか 結構…あぁ、あれなんじゃないかな？そう、なん…て…感じがちょっと難しいな。自分がさ、お姉さん、お姉さんタイプでいいのかって思いながら。お姉さんだよ！お姉さん！お姉さん！…名前明かしてくれそうっていうのが…
It's like, "You're an older sister, right? An older sister type," giving off that reliable vibe...
なんかお姉さん感…
That gives off big "older sister" energy.
なんか本当に、え、マジ、なんだろう。精一杯、精一杯頑張ってる姿とか、うんうん。が、ま、それはさ、なんかお姉さんとか関係なしに、人として、なんか素晴らしいと思うからさ、うん。なんか、そう、そんな感じかな。なんか、特にこういうね、あの、こういうところが良いみたいなさ、ピンポイントで、ちょっと言えなくて申し訳ないけど、ま、人それぞれ一生懸命、うん、うん。うぅ。一生懸命なんか生きてる人は、すごい魅力的だな、って思う。で、そういう人は甘えたいな…
That's really earnest, what, doing your absolute best, and showing that hard-working side—well, that's independent of whether you're an older sister or not, I think it's wonderful, so... something like that? Especially, you know, saying things like "This is the spot!" point-blank might be hard to put into words, sorry, but everyone works super hard!
うわっ！今日はお仕事頑張った！
Hey! Good job today!
褒めて褒めて！褒めて褒めて！
Praise me, praise me! Praise me, praise me!
っていうことですかね？ってやっていいってことですよね？
So that's what it means, right? We can just do that?
え、でもちょっと思うんですけど、その、お姉さんに好かれるってなんかその、甘えん坊とかさ、あの、なんか甘えられるタイプがやっぱりお姉さんに好かれるのかな、みたいな、こう、あの、二次元のっていうか、イメージ、あー、があるじゃないですか。
Right. But I also think, you know, being loved by an older sister type might involve being able to act spoiled or...
[笑]
[Laughs]
ねー！
That kind of image?
ってやっていいってことですよね？
So does that mean it's okay to do that?
だからといって、その、バブバブーって生きるではないよなって思うんですけど、どうでしょうか？
That being said, you can't just go "Babubabu" and expect to survive, you know? What do you think?
え、バブ、バブ、は？バブバブ駄目ですか？
Babubabu? No?
そう。
Right.
いや、なんかそれもそれで可愛くて、愛…そう、ちょっと包容力が、ある。
Well, even that has its own cuteness, so it shows affection.
いや、あり、ありだ。だから、本当に難しい。そう、なんか、こういうことを言って、戦略だと、う、思ってて、この、その、マロ主さんがどういうタイプ？こういうのってさ、あの、なんか、よしよしする人とかじゃな、よしよしじゃなくて、その、タイプの、その、自分は、そう、例えば身長が高いから、そういう、なんか、かっこいい系で、なんかスタイリングとかしてます、とか、逆に、いや自分結構幼い、童顔って言われるから、幼い感じで、とか、そう、そういう、なんか戦略？やっぱ自分にあった感じとかも、うん、うん。
Yeah, true, true. That's why it's really hard. If you talk about strategy, Noel-san, what kind of type...
大事かな、あと性格とかも。
right?
だから、なんだろうな。うん、なんか、どのタイプでもなんか普通に、お姉さんに好かれそう、な気がする。背伸びしてるタイプもバブバブなタイプも、うん。でも逆に、なんか本当にNGなようなことをしなければ、うん。なんか、いいな。清潔か？清潔感や！清潔感や！え？もうこれはあれだね、お姉さんとかお姉さんじゃないとか、もう別で、関係なく人に好かれるということみたいな、
So, what could it be? No matter what type you are, you'd probably naturally be liked by an older sister type if you're trying your best, stretching to your limits, whether you're babubabu or whatever... Conversely, if you don't do anything truly unacceptable, like being unhygienic—wait, unhygienic? Unhygienic, huh? [Laughs]
感じですかね？
feelings, right?
難しい。本当なんかちょっと、いや、むずいね。うん、うん。
Difficult! Truly, like, yeah, it's tough.
これ、こちら難しいんだけど。人にもよるからみたいなところはあるよね。ラミたん、お姉さんとして、としたらどう？
It depends on the person, right? What about Lamy-tan? As an older sister, what would you say?
ラミ、お姉さん属性ある？
Does Lamy have "older sister" traits?
うん、まあんまりない感じ。あるあるあるよ。でも、みんなお姉さんっぽいて言ってるから、この人は。
Well, not really. But everyone says I seem like an older sister, this person says.
おぉ、そうなんだ。ラミにお姉さん属性？いやあ、でも、やっぱお姉さん、まあ関係ないかもな。人としてになっちゃうのかな？やっぱそうだな。
Ohh, is that right? Lamy has "older sister" traits? Well, but maybe "older sister" doesn't matter, you just end up as a person, right? Exactly.
ラミは、やっぱ尊敬できる人が魅力的に、あー、そうだね。見えるから、お仕事頑張ってる、とか、なんか好きなことをなんかね、追っかけてる、とか、なんかそういうところに魅力を感じる、のかな？
Lamy, you find people you can respect to be attractive, right? Like working hard at their job, or chasing after something they love—you feel attraction towards those kinds of things, right?
やっぱあれからね、その、誠実に生きる。のお姉さんとかは一回置いといて、
So, after all, living sincerely... let's set aside "older sisters" for a moment.
え、こよは、こよははどうなの？こよはも、お姉さんのあの、かっていう感じでさ、あるんだけどさ。
Right, what about Koyori? Koyori is like, "What about you, older sister?" right?
でもなんか、やっぱり支え合えるような関係を築きたいていう風に言ってるから、それを大事にしていくことなのかな、と、思えますね。
Even so, you want to build a relationship where you can support each other, right? Since you say that, it's important to cherish that, I suppose.
で、その、でもなんか、お姉さんタイプの女性、って
And also, about "older sister type" women...
決めなくていいのかなと思っていて
I was wondering if maybe we don't need to decide.
なんか
Like...
好きになった人がお姉さんだったならお姉さんだし、
if the person you fall in love with happens to be older, then she is,
もしかしたら全然お姉さんじゃなくても好きになるかもしれないから、この人自身も
or maybe you'll fall for someone completely different, so even for that person...
そのときに、なんか「お姉さんじゃないな」って
at that moment, instead of thinking "she's not an older sister type,"
ならないで、好きになったならその好きになった人と幸せになってほしいなって思います。
if you've come to love someone, I hope you can be happy with the person you've fallen for.
そう。
Exactly.
うんうんうん。
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
幸せ、
Happiness...
幸あれ！幸あれ！
Blessings! Blessings!
幸あれなんだよね。
Wishing for happiness.
なんかちょっとね、一個、今の話の流れでですね、
Yeah, and connected to our current topic,
ちょっと悩んでる人がいるんで、一個だけちょっと個別にいくんですけども、
there's someone worrying about something, so I'd like to pick just one specific question...
あのね、えー、
Um, let's see.
質問です。「女性から見て、恋愛や結婚に前のめりにならず自分のやりたいことに挑戦や目標に向けての行動を最優先して取り組んでいる男性ってどう思いますか？」
Here's a question: "From a woman's perspective, what do you think of men who aren't overly eager about romance or marriage, but instead prioritize pursuing their passions, challenges, and goals?"
って
That's...
うえー！ええやん！
Whoa! That's awesome!
これはなん、えっと、付き合ってる彼女がいてってこと？
What does this mean? Like, while having a girlfriend?
多分、そうゆうことではなく自分自身が恋愛とか結婚とか多分何も興味なく、
Probably not that, but rather, he himself has zero interest in romance or marriage,
仕事に一生懸命なんだと思う。
and is putting his all into his work.
今でもさ、仕事に一生懸命な人って素敵みたいな話があったやん？
Earlier we talked about how admirable someone dedicated to their work is, right?
どう、どう思いますかっていうのは、
So what do we think about that?
ああ、なんか恋愛対象になるかなみたいな話でも、ちょっと考えてみると...
Ah, even when thinking about whether someone becomes a romantic prospect or not, if you ponder it a bit...
いいのかなあ。
maybe it's good.
いやもう、もう要素しかなくて、今ちょっと、あれなんですけど...
Wait, I can only see good things about it right now, so...
なんか、あの、えっと、団長的にこう、個人的にね、思うのが、
Like, um, speaking as Danchou, personally, what I think is...
めちゃめちゃやっぱさ、尊敬できるからさ、すごいなって思う反面、ただ...
on one hand, you can respect them so much that you think they're amazing, but on the other hand...
ただ、隙がないもっとも... もしかしたら近寄り難いみたいな、
however, because they have no openings, they might seem a bit unapproachable,
ああ、そういうところはちょっとある、なんか、
so there's that aspect...
多分恋愛とかってさ、お互いのその歩み寄りだったりその歩幅とかが、
Probably in romance, if the pace and strides you take toward each other are too different,
ちょっと違いすぎると、破綻しちゃうと思うから、
I think it might fall apart, so...
多分このまろ主さんはすごいなって団長は思ったのって、きっと団長もね今こうやってホロライブでさ、活動すごく頑張っててさ、
So Danchou thought this listener was amazing, probably because Danchou herself is working really hard right now in Hololive,
お仕事にこう一筋みたいなところがあるから、なんかどうなのかなっていう気持ちで思ったんだけど、ただ...
and putting everything into her work, so she felt that way, but...
やっぱ、その恋愛とか結婚とかしたいこからすると、
still, from the perspective of someone who wants to date or get married,
ちょっとあれかも、隙がなくて近寄り難いていうのはあるかもなって思った。
you might think it's a bit much, or that they lack openings and feel unapproachable.
素晴らしいです（笑）拍手出てきた！
That's wonderful! (Laughs) Applause!
こよの顔ずっとニコニコしてたよ。
Koyori's face was smiling the whole time.
ニコニコというか、なんこ、これね、すごく素敵じゃん、そのふたりのさっき話してた内容も含めて、すてきやんって思ったの。
Smiling, or rather, like, this is wonderful, considering what the two of you were talking about earlier, I thought it was wonderful.
で、でもこよりは一個この子に伝えたいなって思ったことがあって、
And yet, there's something Koyori wanted to tell this listener:
それはすごく素敵なことだし、とっても人間として素敵なんだけど、
while it's a wonderful and very admirable way to live,
その生活をずっと続けてると何も起きないぞ、気を付けろって...
if you keep living that way, nothing is ever going to happen, so watch out!
こよりからの、そう、
That's what Koyori wanted to say.
で、なんか言うだけは言ってあげたいなって思ったのね。で、それを言って締めようかなぐらいに思って今これをとりあげたんだけど、
So she thought she'd wrap it up by saying that, and that's why she picked this topic,
その理由がもうノエたんの口から全部出たから、すごく拍手でした。
but since Noel already said all the reasons herself, she's giving a big round of applause.
ああ、なるほどね。解決策が出たと思って、
Ah, I see. Thinking that a solution came out,
なんか、その生活をしつつもちょっと隙を、隙作りたいもの、やっぱ結婚とか恋愛とかしたいなと思ったら、隙が必要なんですね、たぶんね。
while living that life, if you want to create openings, if you want to get married or date, you probably need openings.
隙ってなんですか？
What is an opening?
でも隙ってやっぱあれなんだ、なんかさ、多分忙しそうにしてる、なんか、うーん、と、やっぱり、
But an opening is probably like, when someone seems so busy,
あ、忙しいんだなみたいな、じゃあ...
you think, "Ah, they must be so busy, so..."
多分遊ぶ時間もないんだろうなとかさ、そういうの思われちゃいそうだから、
You'd think they probably don't have time to hang out, so you might think that.
普通に趣味も楽しんでますよみたいな、あ、いいね、いいね、仕事だけじゃなくて、趣味を楽しんでるってこと、あ、時間もちょっと余裕があって...
But enjoying your hobbies normally... wait, like enjoying hobbies means you have free time...
そういうのあるのかなとか、そういうとこかな？なんか、まあね、こう、大体的にその恋愛とかちょっと興味ありますとかアピールできればいいけど、それってやりすぎるとちょっと逆にね、あれになっちゃうから、本当にそういう隙かな？趣味とか余裕とかかなって...
might be it. Well, if you can openly appeal that you're interested in romance, great, but if you overdo it, it might have the opposite effect, so is it really about having that kind of opening? Like hobbies or spare time...
なるほどね、すこやみじゃないからねえ
That's right, since it's not "sukoyami"...
ちょっとこよりが言えない、答えられない
Since Koyori can't really answer or say much,
質問だからさ、これさ、うーん、だから、その、ありがたいなと思って、答えてもらえて。
this is a question like that, so I'm really grateful for it.
なるほど。
I see.
で、ラミたんが、その女の子として、
Lamy-tan, as a girl,
なんか好きだと感じるのは、なんか他に何かあったりする？
do you feel like you like anything else?
え、でも、やっぱ趣味は大きいんじゃない？
Well, even so, hobbies are big, right?
うんうんうんうん。
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
やっぱそうだなあ。
Yeah, that's right.
でもさ、この方さ、自分のやりたいことに挑戦してるって書いてあるからさ、
But this person is challenging what they want to do,
ま、お仕事だけじゃなくて、自分のやりたいこともできてるってことでしょう？
so it's not just work, but doing what you want to do too, right?
うん、たぶん、たぶん。
Yeah, probably, probably.
うんうん。
Yeah, yeah.
すごくいいと思うけどね、めちゃくちゃ素敵なだとも思いますよ。
I think it's really good, very wonderful.
うん、そうね、素晴らしい。
Yeah.
うん。
じゃあさ、あのさ、この人たぶんまだ好きな人とかいるわけじゃないと思うんだけど、
This person probably doesn't have a favorite person yet, but...
あの、趣味を満喫して、そういう雰囲気出すのに、なんかちょっとストラップとかつけてみるとか、
to enjoy your hobbies and create that atmosphere, maybe putting on a strap or something...
うん。
Yeah.
例えばさ、我々のようなちいかわ好きとかだったら、ちいかわのキーホルダーつけてたりすると、
Like if you're into Chikawa, having a Chikawa key holder...
あ、ちいかわのスキン推し活したりしてるのかな、みたいな。
"Oh, they like Chikawa" or something.
ところから、なんか会話が生まれたりとかね。
That sparks conversation, right?
ある、なんかそういうのどうですかね？なんか何もつけてないとかだったら。
What if you don't have anything attached?
うん、なんかまあ、その仕事とかね、普段のそういうTPOにもよるけど、
Well, that depends on your job or daily routine.
たしかにたしかに。
True, true.
うん、でもなんか団長めっちゃいいなって思った。
I thought leader-chan is really good.
なんかその、それ、それも好きではあるかなっていうね。
I think that's also nice.
良いと思う。
I think it's great.
なんかさっきのね、マシュマロの人もいたけどさ、ちいかわ1人でね、男性見たいけどみてってたけど、
Like earlier, some marshmallow person said Chikawa should do it alone with guys, but...
いや、普通にそれって、なんか可愛いポイントだと男性は思うから、
Actually, guys think that's a cute point, right?
なんかね、そういう、ね、マスコットとか、まあ、物にもよるのかもしれない、職場にね、つけてだから、なんかいいなって思う。うん。
Having a mascot or something attached to your workplace is nice.
思います。
I think so.
そうね、うん。話しかけるきっかけになりそうですね。
It's a great catalyst for starting a conversation.
うん、そういう好きを作りつつも、お仕事頑張る君は素敵だよということでね。うん、はい。
So, while making those likes, working hard guys are wonderful!
はい、えらい！
Great!
で、え、締めたいと思います。
Let's wrap it up.
シモシちょっと広いのがいろいろあって、えー、時間ちょっとナッチャターンですけれども、今日はどうでしたか？のえたん。
Today was how's the enetan?
いや、もう出れてよかった。楽しかった！
Well, I'm glad I came out, it was fun!
もうちょっと、うん、すごいさ、なかなかやっぱね、このガチトークだから、本当にガチな話いろいろ聞けたりできたりして、
And since this is "Gachi Talk", we can talk about real things.
あと、マシュマロでもね、こういう悩んでる子がこんなにたくさんいるんだと思って。
And marshmallow has so many people worrying like this.
さ、一個だけ、ちょっと、団長さ、脱毛のデメリット言うの忘れた。
Just one thing, about whole body hair removal...
ちょっと、これだけ伝えたい、全身脱毛にの、話なんだけど。
This is about full body hair removal.
あのね、毛が、あの、ないからさ、あの、泡立たなくなった！ボディソープが！
Since there's no hair, body soap got bubbly!
え？そんなことある？そんなことある？
Wait, really? Is that a thing?
あの、団長、今までさ、こう、何にもね、その、あの、全身脱毛したことあるんだけど、
I've done full body hair removal,
で、でも昔はさ、学生のときとかはさ、この、なんか全然毛とかあったからさ、泡立たってたのよ、体。
but back when I was a student, my body had hair so it was bubbly.
だから、そのわざわざこうゴシゴシする、なんていうの？ボディソープをさ、泡立てるさ、バスタオルみたいなのあるじゃん。
So scrubbing with body soap and bath towels used to work.
あいうのを使わなくてよかったんだけど、なんか毛がなくなったら、そう、するするで、もうなんかさ、
You didn't need those, but once you don't have hair...
泡立てなきゃいけなくなった。毛で泡立てててたの？
You have to make it bubbly yourself!
そんなわけないでしょ！
Wait, no way!
いや、泡立たって、なんか、どんだけ生えてた？どんだけ生えてた？
Was it really that bubbly before?
ボディソープの問題じゃないのか。まあいろいろあるかもしれないけど、もしかしたらね、この脱毛考えてる人で、自分も毛で泡立ててて、っていう人がいた、
Maybe it's not a body soap issue, but if you're thinking about hair removal...
そこはデメリットになるから気をつけたほうがいいかっていうので、そこだけね、神経の話かなって思ったけど、なんか、え？みたいな。
That becomes a demerit, so be careful!
あ、泡泡になるさ、あの、なんていうの？もふもふもふってなってるやつ使ってんだよね、こゆり。
Ah, to make bubbles, you use those bubbly net things.
あの、泡立てができるやつ。あの、編み編みになってる、あみあみがふわふぁふぁふぁって集まってるやつ。あれ使えば最初からびゃあって泡立たって、そのまま滑らせればオッケーだね。
Those mesh nets that make foam instantly are amazing.
あれ、あれすごい、あれ革命よな。
That's a revolution!
だから、その全身脱毛する人はそれを買ってく。
So people doing full body hair removal should buy that.
せーの！あっ！ち、ち、ちょーっと！
Let's go!
おやすみなさーい！
Good night!